<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>ccmArchive20130409</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.Admin</creator>
  <creationDate>1365482943000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.Admin</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.Admin</contentAuthor>
  <date>1365548312000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1365548312000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.247</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #ccm on 09 April 2013</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;ravigarg27> has joined #ccm
02:26 &lt;phd> has joined #ccm
03:54 &lt;qwebirc1228> has joined #ccm
03:54 &lt;qwebirc1228> Hi
03:54 &lt;qwebirc1228> may I know what system is the phenotip built on
06:28 &lt;BogdanVancea> has joined #ccm
06:32 &lt;phoenix_ukr> has joined #ccm
07:39 &lt;BogdanVancea> has left #ccm
07:45 &lt;BogdanVancea> has joined #ccm
07:51 &lt;krinye> has joined #ccm
07:52 &lt;krinye> Hello anyone I can talk to about google summer of code?
08:05 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
08:16 &lt;BogdanVancea> has joined #ccm
08:30 &lt;krinye> has joined #ccm
08:30 &lt;krinye> Hello any mentors around?
08:30 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi krinye
08:31 &lt;krinye> hello, I was wondering if I could get more information about the android app projects
08:31 &lt;krinye> e.g. safe heart and the mobile app for chronic disease
08:32 &lt;sdumitriu> Trying to get Marc in here
08:33 &lt;sdumitriu> Maybe I can help
08:34 &lt;sdumitriu> So, what do you want to know?
08:34 &lt;krinye> Any help would be greatly appreciated.
08:34 &lt;krinye> are these projects run in conjunction with the Centre of Global ehealth Innovation?
08:35 &lt;krinye> Is there a development wiki that explains what has been developed so far?
08:36 &lt;krinye> Do you participate in any of the hacking health events in Vancouver, Toronto and Montreal?
08:38 &lt;krinye> Are students working on projects alone or do they work in a team enviroment? especially within the Centre of eHealth Innovation, Can we tap into their resources?
08:38 &lt;mfiume> has joined #ccm
08:38 &lt;sdumitriu> Ah, good, Marc is here
08:39 &lt;mfiume> Hello, I'm the mentor for the potential SafeHeart project
08:39 &lt;mfiume> @krinye did you have questions?
08:39 &lt;sdumitriu> http://phenotips.org/IRC/ccmArchive20130409
08:42 &lt;mfiume> Our mobile apps are sometimes run in conjunction with eHealth innovation
08:42 &lt;mfiume> We do participate in Hacking Health. We recently participated in the event in Toronto
08:44 &lt;mfiume> There is currently no wiki set up for the project. It was actually developed as part of a course project, which attracted a lot of attention from SickKids. We're now in the process of branding it as a SickKids app.
08:44 &lt;mfiume> I can send you a written document outlining the features of the app, we will be preparing that for April 12
08:46 &lt;mfiume> We have a good relationship with the Centre for eHealth Innovation. If there is need and interest for their resources, then we can certainly do so.
08:51 &lt;krinye> nice, can I send my GSOC application early to have the timelines reviewed?
08:51 &lt;krinye> In addition, out of curiosity what project did you work on at last years Hacking Health
09:01 &lt;mfiume> I wasn't there myself, another member of our team Adam McKillop was there. His project was related to SafeHeart, although under a different name
09:01 &lt;krinye> I have to duck to Robarts but I will email you to get the documentation on the projects. If worst comes to worst I shall meet you guys hopefully at the next hacking health
09:01 &lt;krinye> thanks for the time and the help answering my questions, cheers
09:02 &lt;mfiume> Great!
09:02 &lt;mfiume> has left #ccm
09:21 &lt;phenotips_org> has joined #ccm
11:08 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
11:46 &lt;krinye> has joined #ccm
13:45 &lt;krinye> has joined #ccm
14:34 &lt;qwebirc24207> has joined #ccm
14:51 &lt;RenatoM> has joined #ccm
14:52 &lt;RenatoM> Hi there
14:52 &lt;RenatoM> may I talk to Sergiu please?
14:52 &lt;sdumitriu1> Hi RenatoM
14:53 &lt;sdumitriu1> Unfortunately Marc just left a few seconds ago for a meeting, so it will be just me
14:53 &lt;RenatoM> Hi how are you?
14:53 &lt;RenatoM> ok no problem
14:54 &lt;RenatoM> I just didn't know what time exactly to get into IRC
14:54 &lt;RenatoM> anyways about your questions
14:54 &lt;sdumitriu1> I'm fine, trying to code a few issues needed for the next PhenoTips release
14:54 &lt;RenatoM> my two students are pretty much done, they have to present their work by the end of April
14:54 &lt;RenatoM> and they are just correcting their writing (:
14:55 &lt;RenatoM> nice!
14:56 &lt;sdumitriu1> OK, I hope they did well
14:59 &lt;sdumitriu1> What about the other things? As far as I've gathered from WikiPedia, in Peru school lasts from March to December
15:02 &lt;RenatoM> has joined #ccm
15:04 &lt;RenatoM> Sergiu are you still there?
15:04 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yes, you timed out
15:04 &lt;sdumitriu1> What about the other things? As far as I've gathered from WikiPedia, in Peru school lasts from March to December
15:05 &lt;RenatoM> Yeah I am a part time professor at a local university here in Peru
15:05 &lt;RenatoM> I teach at most 20 hours
15:05 &lt;RenatoM> mainly practical stuff
15:06 &lt;RenatoM> databases or oop
15:06 &lt;RenatoM> is the project a difficult project?
15:07 &lt;sdumitriu1> Let's see
15:07 &lt;sdumitriu1> Real-time collection of clinical data on patients with genetic disorders using various medical ontologies
15:07 &lt;sdumitriu1> That one shouldn't be too long
15:07 &lt;RenatoM> yeah that one, I mean what are you guys planning to do?
15:08 &lt;RenatoM> is it just collecting the data from specific sources and integrating it into Solr?
15:08 &lt;sdumitriu1> Basically it involves adapting what's already done for HPO to work for other ontologies
15:08 &lt;RenatoM> or are you planning to do some entity extraction, deduplication and disambiguation
15:08 &lt;sdumitriu1> Get hold of ICD10 or LDD
15:08 &lt;sdumitriu1> See what fields it contains
15:09 &lt;sdumitriu1> Index the relevant fields in Solr
15:09 &lt;sdumitriu1> Add a component that can query the correct fields
15:10 &lt;sdumitriu1> Make it easily configurable to switch between ontologies
15:10 &lt;sdumitriu1> Did you try the PhenoTips demo?
15:11 &lt;RenatoM_> has joined #ccm
15:11 &lt;RenatoM_> Ok I am back
15:11 &lt;RenatoM_> sorry about that
15:11 &lt;RenatoM_> I keep timing out
15:12 &lt;RenatoM_> so how do you guys choose "relevant" information?
15:12 &lt;RenatoM_> how do you extract that information out?
15:12 &lt;sdumitriu1> You can find the logs here: http://phenotips.org/IRC/ccmArchive20130409
15:12 &lt;RenatoM_> I am familiar with Apache Nutch but that is more of an offline IR system
15:13 &lt;sdumitriu1> Nutch extends Solr, which in turn extends Lucene
15:13 &lt;RenatoM_> s
15:13 &lt;RenatoM_> yeah
15:13 &lt;RenatoM_> I have use it with Solr
15:13 &lt;RenatoM_> but it is not a real time solution
15:14 &lt;sdumitriu1> Well, the project isn't so much about extracting information
15:14 &lt;sdumitriu1> That would be this other project https://gsoc.ccm.sickkids.ca/GoogleSummerOfCode/Extraction+of+ontology+terms+from+free+form+clinical+notes
15:14 &lt;RenatoM_> ok (:
15:14 &lt;sdumitriu1> So, did you try the PhenoTips demo?
15:15 &lt;RenatoM_> no I couldn't
15:15 &lt;RenatoM_> I tried but it didn't go nowhere
15:15 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yeah, I noticed somebody spammed the page, fixed it a few hours ago
15:15 &lt;RenatoM_> could you please point me to the correct url?
15:15 &lt;sdumitriu1> http://phenotips.org/edit/data/P0000001#HClinicalsymptoms26physicalfindings
15:16 &lt;RenatoM_> ok
15:16 &lt;RenatoM_> I am seeing it now
15:16 &lt;RenatoM_> (:
15:16 &lt;RenatoM_> thanks
15:16 &lt;sdumitriu1> So the main idea of PhenoTips is that it stores patient phenotypes (observed anomalities) using standard terms from the Human Phenotype Ontology
15:17 &lt;RenatoM_> I understand now
15:18 &lt;RenatoM_> and you want to integrate it with icd10
15:18 &lt;sdumitriu1&gt; So the checked phenotypes, like "Intellectual disability, moderate" or "Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder" are actually stored as HP:0002342 and HP:0007018
15:18 &lt;RenatoM_> like adding an extra functionality with it?
15:19 &lt;RenatoM_> interesting
15:19 &lt;sdumitriu1> Also, if you use the Quick Phenotype Search bar, you can use free text, and in the backend we use Solr to match the user text to the most relevant terms from HPO
15:19 &lt;RenatoM_> so the HP is an annotation from the Human Phenotype Ontology
15:20 &lt;sdumitriu1> Now, while we like HPO because it's open, it's easy to improve, and so far it's pretty comprehensive, most existing applications use other standards
15:20 &lt;sdumitriu1> Almost every hospital where we deployed PhenoTips asked about ICD10
15:21 &lt;sdumitriu1> So the goal is to do the same thing that's happening now, but instead of using terms from HPO, use terms from ICD10 or LDD
15:21 &lt;RenatoM_> so does phenotips actually store user information? I mean peoples deceases
15:21 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yes
15:22 &lt;sdumitriu1> (the demo is not for storing real patient data, that's highly confidential)
15:22 &lt;sdumitriu1> For example, http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ADHD does list on the infobox the ICD10 ID for ADHD (F90 in this case)
15:23 &lt;RenatoM_> man that is really cool system
15:23 &lt;RenatoM_> I hadn't understand it
15:25 &lt;RenatoM_> so in which level would the ICD10 be integrated?
15:25 &lt;RenatoM_> at the HPO level?
15:25 &lt;sdumitriu1> Hm...
15:25 &lt;sdumitriu1> Not quite, they will be separate
15:26 &lt;sdumitriu1&gt; Solr allows multiple "cores" to exist in the same instance
15:26 &lt;sdumitriu1> We already have two, one with HPO and another with the OMIM&lt;->HPO mapping
15:26 &lt;RenatoM_> you mean like different collections ??
15:27 &lt;RenatoM_> I see
15:27 &lt;sdumitriu1> OMIM is another ontology, this time with actual diseases, not symptoms
15:27 &lt;RenatoM_> and how do you do the mapping? at the application level?
15:27 &lt;sdumitriu1> And at the bottom of the symptoms there's a Diagnosis section
15:27 &lt;sdumitriu1> So, ICD10 should be another core
15:27 &lt;sdumitriu1> We then have a small Java component that can query the right core
15:28 &lt;sdumitriu1> Plus two documents in the wiki that process the user's terms into a real query
15:28 &lt;RenatoM_> I understand
15:29 &lt;RenatoM_> so the web application is using hibernate or some other java tool?
15:30 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yes, it uses Hibernate
15:30 &lt;RenatoM_> what do you mean by two other documents? ontologies?
15:30 &lt;sdumitriu1> http://phenotips.org/PhenoTips/SolrService?viewer=code
15:31 &lt;sdumitriu1> This makes the connection from the web part to the backend
15:32 &lt;RenatoM_> I understand
15:32 &lt;RenatoM_> so does ICD10 have any endpoint where to get the data from?
15:32 &lt;sdumitriu1> https://github.com/compbio-UofT/phenotips/blob/master/resources/ui/src/main/resources/PhenoTips/PatientSheetCode.xml#L933-946
15:33 &lt;sdumitriu1> This one is where the fields to search in are configured
15:33 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yes, but it's hard to find...
15:33 &lt;sdumitriu1> I have the link saved somewhere, I'll have to look for it
15:34 &lt;sdumitriu1> I think this is it: ftp://ftp.cdc.gov/pub/Health_Statistics/NCHS/Publications/ICD10CM/2012/
15:34 &lt;sdumitriu1> Hm, there's a new release for 2013
15:34 &lt;sdumitriu1> http://www.cdc.gov/nchs/icd/icd10cm.htm#10update
15:35 &lt;RenatoM_> nice!
15:35 &lt;RenatoM_> so part of the project would be to upload it to phenotips servers?
15:36 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yes
15:37 &lt;RenatoM_> ok
15:37 &lt;sdumitriu1> Currently we're manually committing the indexed HPO in https://github.com/compbio-UofT/phenotips/tree/master/resources/solr-configuration/src/main/resources/hpo/data
15:37 &lt;RenatoM_> it is all very interesting Sergiu
15:37 &lt;sdumitriu1> But there's a plan to change that so that the index is built automatically at build time
15:37 &lt;RenatoM_> so maybe we could build a data pipeline for this
15:37 &lt;RenatoM_> yeah that would be the proper way to do it
15:38 &lt;sdumitriu1> I know, but nobody had the time to do this
15:38 &lt;sdumitriu1> Are you familiar with Maven?
15:40 &lt;RenatoM_> yes I am
15:40 &lt;RenatoM_> I am not fluent in maven
15:40 &lt;RenatoM_> but I can get around doing what I need
15:40 &lt;sdumitriu1> No problem, that's all that's needed
15:41 &lt;RenatoM_> good
15:42 &lt;sdumitriu1> So, how does it sound so far?
15:42 &lt;RenatoM_> so is this project part of the Univ. of Toronto? I mean some specific department?
15:42 &lt;RenatoM_> it sounds great man
15:42 &lt;RenatoM_> I think it is pretty much straight forward
15:42 &lt;RenatoM_> 1. getting all the data from icd10
15:42 &lt;RenatoM_> 2. putting into solr
15:42 &lt;RenatoM_> 3. adding this functionality to phenotips
15:43 &lt;sdumitriu1> Hard to say, let's say yes, most of the developers so far are getting paid by the computational biology lab in the computer science department of the university of Toronto
15:43 &lt;RenatoM_> 4. building a data pipeline to put new data into the system
15:44 &lt;sdumitriu1> But it's not owned by the university, it's fully open source
15:45 &lt;RenatoM_> I understand
15:45 &lt;RenatoM_> and have you guys thought about internationalization?
15:45 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yes
15:46 &lt;sdumitriu1> It's going to happen, but not soon
15:46 &lt;sdumitriu1> I mean, most of the UI should already work in other languages
15:46 &lt;sdumitriu1> But the ontology is not yet available in other languages
15:47 &lt;RenatoM_> that is right
15:47 &lt;sdumitriu1> The HPO team says that someone is almost done with a german translation
15:47 &lt;sdumitriu1> And others are working on a few other languages
15:47 &lt;sdumitriu1> And that's why I like the open nature of HPO
15:48 &lt;RenatoM_> that is why I like open source
15:48 &lt;RenatoM_> (:
15:48 &lt;RenatoM_> ok Sergiu
15:49 &lt;RenatoM_> I think I have a pretty good idea how things work, and what needs to be done
15:49 &lt;sdumitriu1> Great
15:49 &lt;RenatoM_> in terms of time, how long do you think this tasks should take?
15:49 &lt;sdumitriu1> I'm never a good time estimator
15:49 &lt;sdumitriu1> I'm sure there will be unforseen problems
15:50 &lt;sdumitriu1> The steps by themselves seem straightforward
15:50 &lt;sdumitriu1> So it shouldn't take more than a month of serious work
15:54 &lt;RenatoM_> roget that
15:54 &lt;RenatoM_> roger that man
15:54 &lt;RenatoM_> so what would the next steps be?
15:54 &lt;RenatoM_> I mean applying through the Melange site?
15:54 &lt;RenatoM_> do you think I would be able to complete the amount of work needed?
15:55 &lt;sdumitriu1> Yes, even with your other attributions
15:55 &lt;RenatoM_> I mean I have around 15-20 hours less due to the university
15:55 &lt;RenatoM_> (:
15:55 &lt;sdumitriu1> There's still a few days until the registration opens
15:55 &lt;RenatoM_> ok then
15:55 &lt;sdumitriu1> So, until then get working on the proposal
15:55 &lt;sdumitriu1> You can already start to look into the coe
15:55 &lt;sdumitriu1> code
15:56 &lt;sdumitriu1> I've been setting up http://phenotips.org/Community/
15:56 &lt;sdumitriu1> It's still thin, but you should have enough information there to get you started
15:57 &lt;RenatoM_> thank you Sergiu
15:57 &lt;RenatoM_> I will start there
16:00 &lt;RenatoM_> Thanks for your time
16:00 &lt;RenatoM_> I will start there
16:00 &lt;RenatoM_> and be writing to you about stuff
16:01 &lt;RenatoM_> hey just one last question
16:01 &lt;RenatoM_> where did you go to school?
16:01 &lt;RenatoM_> I mean are you a phd already?
16:02 &lt;sdumitriu1> I've done up to MSc in Romania
16:02 &lt;sdumitriu1> And the PhD started in France, but I decided not to finish it and instead write real code
16:03 &lt;RenatoM_> :D
16:03 &lt;RenatoM_> I know what you mean
16:03 &lt;RenatoM_> yeah that is why I haven't looked for a phd just yet
16:03 &lt;RenatoM_> but I feel I need to learn some more extra stuff
16:03 &lt;RenatoM_> just don't know where yet
16:04 &lt;RenatoM_> ok mate
16:05 &lt;RenatoM_> thanks again for all the help
16:05 &lt;RenatoM_> and I will be getting in touch with you
16:05 &lt;RenatoM_> with questions or whatever (:
16:06 &lt;sdumitriu1> Sure
16:06 &lt;sdumitriu1> Ah, I'll be away the rest of the week
16:07 &lt;sdumitriu1> I'll try to read my email, though
16:07 &lt;RenatoM_> thanks again mate
16:07 &lt;RenatoM_> keep well
16:07 &lt;RenatoM_> ttyl
17:26 &lt;mehitabe1> has joined #ccm
17:26 &lt;BogdanVancea> has joined #ccm
18:58 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.ccmArchive20130409</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>56cc2185-405f-4bc4-9507-497aefccc9e4</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>ccm</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>