<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>ccmArchive20140318</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.sdumitriu</creator>
  <creationDate>1395115535000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.sdumitriu</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.sdumitriu</contentAuthor>
  <date>1395198083000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1395198083000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.104</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #ccm on 18 March 2014</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;ruthgrace> my first pull request :)
00:05 &lt;ruthgrace> Thanks @sdumitriu !
00:07 &lt;sdumitriu> You're welcome
01:42 &lt;ruthgrace> Hey @sdumitriu, would you be willing to look over the first draft of my project proposal?
01:42 &lt;ruthgrace> And give me some feedback?
01:42 &lt;sdumitriu> Sure
01:46 &lt;ruthgrace> I uploaded it here: http://ruthgrace.weebly.com/gsoc-proposal.html
01:46 &lt;ruthgrace> any and all criticisms are welcome! :)
01:46 &lt;ruthgrace> thank you so much!
01:47 &lt;ruthgrace> I haven't uploaded any code samples yet, so that section has no links.
01:47 &lt;sdumitriu> Cool, LaTeX!
01:47 &lt;ruthgrace> :)
01:48 &lt;ruthgrace> Do you think I should have some sort of flowchart or graphic to display the tentative archetecture in a way that is more easy to read?
01:49 &lt;ruthgrace> Also I am generally worried that I will lose marks on not having enough actual programming experience. My lab work consists largely of scripting, rather than making actual programs.
01:49 &lt;sdumitriu> Did you read the papers that Asha suggested?
01:50 &lt;ruthgrace> Yes, the pathway analysis one
01:51 &lt;ruthgrace> He actually suggested to me that we start with the simple Over-Representation Analysis and move on to Functional Class Scoring after that
01:51 &lt;ruthgrace> Sorry, I should say that the paper he linked me talked about Over-Representation analysis, which is the easiest, then Functional Class Scoring, and finally 3rd generation analysis
01:52 &lt;ruthgrace> Asha is working on a 3rd generation  analysis approach, and he said that we could implement that if it works out.
01:52 &lt;sdumitriu> Typo: it's architecture, not archetecture
01:52 &lt;ruthgrace> Whoops, thank you !
01:54 &lt;ruthgrace> Are you a bioinformatician?
01:55 &lt;sdumitriu> No, pure software developer
01:55 &lt;sdumitriu> Previous open source: you could mention your experience as a user
01:55 &lt;ruthgrace> Oh, good idea. Thank you.
01:57 &lt;sdumitriu> OK, looks good so far
01:57 &lt;sdumitriu> Personally, I would like to see more details from the implementation perspective
01:57 &lt;ruthgrace> Sure. Should that be a part of the proposal? I was going to write out some skeleton classes with empty methods.
01:58 &lt;ruthgrace> Would it be appropriate to put those details there? Or is it alright to make the Tentative Architecture section really big
01:58 &lt;sdumitriu> The architecture part details the scientific side well, and I guess that for this project it's important to have that pinned down
01:58 &lt;sdumitriu> But for most "software" projects in GSoC, architecture usually means how the code will be organized
01:59 &lt;ruthgrace> Ooohhhh
01:59 &lt;sdumitriu> If you make a stub of the implementation, and just link to it from the proposal, I guess that should work
01:59 &lt;ruthgrace> Perhaps I can split it up into a section about how the code will be organized, and another section about the scientific aspects
02:00 &lt;sdumitriu> Code "speaks" better than words
02:00 &lt;ruthgrace> That will be much less messy :)
02:00 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
02:04 &lt;ruthgrace> Do you think it's worth sending my next proposal draft to the ccm-mentors email for feedback?
02:05 &lt;sdumitriu> You should submit it through Melange
02:36 &lt;ruthgrace> I am exhausted! I will deal with my code samples tomorrow. Have a good night, @sdumitriu ! Thank you for everything.
02:36 &lt;sdumitriu> You're welcome
02:36 &lt;sdumitriu> Good night
03:32 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
03:41 &lt;tweety098> Hi I'm interested in working on the project 'Development of machine learning methods for modeling the evolution o tumors'
03:43 &lt;tweety098> I'm going through the source code provided. Can anyone guide me as to where do I get started as in what code patches should I work upon?
06:03 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
07:41 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
08:26 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
08:50 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
09:35 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
10:12 &lt;tweety098> ?
10:12 &lt;tweety098> ?
10:25 &lt;shalini479> has joined #ccm
10:25 &lt;shalini479> has left #ccm
10:25 &lt;shalini479> has joined #ccm
10:30 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
10:42 &lt;sdumitriu1> has joined #ccm
10:48 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
10:49 &lt;ruthgrace> has joined #ccm
10:50 &lt;ruthgrace> @sdumitriu_: Linux mint isn't one of the OSs that infobright supports. :( I'll try today on Windows 7.
11:36 &lt;ruthgrace> has joined #ccm
11:36 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
12:34 &lt;ruthgrace> has joined #ccm
12:45 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
12:53 &lt;shalini479> has joined #ccm
12:57 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
13:04 &lt;SayAsh_> has joined #ccm
13:16 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
13:34 &lt;shalini479> has left #ccm
13:56 &lt;SayAsh> has joined #ccm
14:54 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
18:01 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
19:11 &lt;Shubham> has joined #ccm
19:11 &lt;Shubham> Hi !
19:22 &lt;Shubham> has joined #ccm
19:34 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi Shubham
19:35 &lt;Shubham> Hi sdumitriu. I have submitted my first proposal. Would you like to suggest some improvements I can make ?
19:36 &lt;Shubham> Its the first draft. So, brutal scrutiny will be appreciated :)
19:37 &lt;sdumitriu> Not today, sorry, I was just about to leave
20:00 &lt;Shubham> has joined #ccm
20:29 &lt;ruthgrace> has joined #ccm
20:33 &lt;Shubham> has joined #ccm
20:35 &lt;ruthgrace> Hi, when running the MedSavant client, what should I put in for DATABASE ?
20:36 &lt;ruthgrace> I think HOSTNAME is localhost and PORT is 5029, but i'm not sure what the database name is
20:36 &lt;ruthgrace> do i have to make one ?
20:36 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
20:39 &lt;ruthgrace> Do you have sample data to load in?
20:40 &lt;sdumitriu> Marc should know where to find it
20:40 &lt;sdumitriu> But you can look for VCF files
20:40 &lt;ruthgrace> Okay. Thank you!
21:09 &lt;ruthgrace> hey tweety
21:09 &lt;ruthgrace> are you going to try to do a MedSavant project?
21:44 &lt;woohee> has joined #ccm
21:45 &lt;woohee> good evening
21:51 &lt;ruthgrace> has joined #ccm
21:55 &lt;groundnuty> has joined #ccm
21:57 &lt;groundnuty> Greetings, I'm a PhD student from Poland and I'm strongly considering applying for one of your Proposals connected with PhyloSub
21:57 &lt;groundnuty> preferably the one connected with rewriting the code from Python to C++
22:00 &lt;groundnuty> I had truble judging how detailed description of architecture/timeling is required and after trying to consult this on #gosc I was adviced to ask the mentoring organization
22:04 &lt;groundnuty> if possible I would be greatefull for any information on that subject
22:34 &lt;ruthgrace> has joined #ccm
22:59 &lt;ruthgrace> @sdumitriu sorry, dumb question, but how do I make a database using the infobright mysqld server?
23:00 &lt;ruthgrace> I've managed to set it up so that the server is running under the username mysql and I don't have access to it even as root
23:01 &lt;ruthgrace> (I switched back to linux mint - I think I just didn't sudo something before, because for some reason the servers are working now)</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.ccmArchive20140318</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>6b8321c8-33de-4a87-8705-dba77bb6fa23</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>ccm</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>