<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>ccmArchive20140225</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.sdumitriu</creator>
  <creationDate>1393309363000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.sdumitriu</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.sdumitriu</contentAuthor>
  <date>1393383716000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1393383716000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.102</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #ccm on 25 February 2014</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;qwebirc19402> has joined #ccm
02:55 &lt;qwebirc71202> has joined #ccm
02:55 &lt;qwebirc71202> HI Everyone
02:56 &lt;qwebirc71202> I would like to learn more about "Visualising the Evolution of Tumors" project
02:56 &lt;qwebirc71202> Where can I get the wiki or the expectation list for the particular project
03:55 &lt;raghav> has joined #ccm
03:57 &lt;raghav> Hi everyone
05:24 &lt;raghav> has joined #ccm
05:58 &lt;raghav> has joined #ccm
08:08 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
08:14 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
08:29 &lt;nclandrei_> has joined #ccm
08:29 &lt;nclandrei_> hi everyone
08:29 &lt;nclandrei_> this is the right place to ask about GSoC projects, right?
08:40 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
10:24 &lt;nclandrei_> has joined #ccm
10:25 &lt;nclandrei__> has joined #ccm
10:37 &lt;rays2pix> has joined #ccm
10:37 &lt;rays2pix> Hi I am interested in the project "Developing machine learning  methods"
10:50 &lt;sdumitriu_[away]&gt; Hi rays2pix
11:04 &lt;rays2pix> Hi Sdumitriu
11:06 &lt;sdumitriu> That is Quaid's project, he's rarely on IRC, so you should write by email to quaid.morris@utoronto.ca and CC ccm-mentors@cs.toronto.edu
11:08 &lt;rays2pix> Thank you. I have already mailed to ccm-mentors. Will forward it to quaid.
11:10 &lt;sdumitriu> You're Deepak?
11:14 &lt;rays2pix> yes
11:18 &lt;rays2pix> sdumitriu, :Which project will you be mentoring?
11:19 &lt;sdumitriu> I don't know yet, it depends on what students like
11:19 &lt;sdumitriu> But I'm mostly a PhenoTips developer
11:20 &lt;rays2pix> oh okay
11:25 &lt;root_l> has joined #ccm
11:26 &lt;root_l> hope i landed where its about "Computational Medecine"
11:26 &lt;root_l> i was directed here from a GSOC page
11:26 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi root_l, yes
11:27 &lt;root_l> am a newbiew to GSOC and after visiting your ideas page, i think i liked one or two ideas from there
11:30 &lt;sdumitriu> Which ones?
11:31 &lt;root_l> i was particulary attracted by the "Diagnostic apps for medical genomics"
11:31 &lt;root_l> and also the "mobile UI for the pedigree tool"
11:32 &lt;sosna> has joined #ccm
11:33 &lt;root_l> i need more info about these , like what are the pre-requisites, already existing prototypes and stuff like that
11:41 &lt;sdumitriu> Hold on, talking with someone else
11:42 &lt;root_l> ok
11:58 &lt;sdumitriu> root_l: OK, for the Diagnostic apps, you should contact Ron directly by email (CC ccm-mentors), since that's his personal project
11:59 &lt;sdumitriu> For the pedigree, you should /join #phenotips
11:59 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: ok . i'll try
12:00 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: but don't they come here?
12:00 &lt;sdumitriu> Rarely, this year we were actually going to not use the IRC channel
12:00 &lt;sdumitriu> It's just me here redirecting students to the proper place
12:01 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: oh, ok i c
12:01 &lt;sdumitriu> This younger generation doesn't like IRC anymore...
12:02 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: but i have been redirected to another channel. am on it now
13:18 &lt;sosna> has joined #ccm
14:03 &lt;nclandrei> has joined #ccm
14:03 &lt;nclandrei> hi everyone
14:04 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi nclandrei
14:04 &lt;nclandrei> is this the right place to talk about GSoC projects?
14:04 &lt;nclandrei> (-:
14:05 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
14:05 &lt;sdumitriu> Kind of
14:05 &lt;sdumitriu> Quaid isn't usually here
14:06 &lt;root_l> we're on #phenotips
14:06 &lt;nclandrei> I have researched on the list published on Melange and I came to the conclusion that the best opportunity would be to work with you, guys
14:06 &lt;nclandrei> oh, should I come there?
14:06 &lt;sdumitriu> He's usually busy (as a professor/researcher), so the best way to contact him is by personal email (it's listed under the project)
14:06 &lt;sdumitriu> But I can help you a bit
14:07 &lt;sdumitriu> You're a first year student, right?
14:07 &lt;nclandrei> Well I have sent an email, but I've received no reply so I wanted to get help from anywhere possible
14:07 &lt;nclandrei> yes, I am
14:07 &lt;nclandrei> first year student at Jacobs university, in Bremen
14:09 &lt;sdumitriu> I'm not sure what Quaid expects for his projects, but my honest opinion is that you'd need a bit more experience for those
14:10 &lt;sdumitriu> Especially with machine learning and computer vision
14:10 &lt;nclandrei> well I have seen the requirements and they do not seem possible.. I have studied computer science since 7/8th grade
14:10 &lt;nclandrei> and now I am working for the german research center for artificial intelligence and robotics
14:11 &lt;nclandrei> + I have completed a courseera machine learning course, so I kind of have some experience
14:11 &lt;sdumitriu> OK, that's good
14:13 &lt;nclandrei> now I am working with image processing, using openCV mainly, so I am used to these types of projects
14:13 &lt;nclandrei> + I am very, extremely keen to learn more in order to be able to participate in one of your projects
14:13 &lt;sdumitriu> Oh, that's interesting
14:13 &lt;nclandrei> because the idea and having the chance to work on such a helpful project for other people's health is amazing
14:14 &lt;sdumitriu> So you're quite advanced for a first year student
14:14 &lt;nclandrei> even back in Romania I have participated in a lot of contests etc. for CS
14:14 &lt;nclandrei> so yes (-:
14:14 &lt;nclandrei> offtopic: my mother is a CS teacher haha
14:18 &lt;sdumitriu> So, you don't like any of the PhenoTips projects?
14:20 &lt;nclandrei> well I was also very interested in this one: Multiple visits support in PhenoTips
14:20 &lt;nclandrei> I think I can handle what pre-req. are there
14:21 &lt;nclandrei> unfortunately, I don't have that much experience with jGit, but I can start learning before the program starts
14:21 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes, that's a hard but interesting project
14:23 &lt;nclandrei> so what would be the following steps, what should I do in order to maybe increase my chances of being accepted?
14:23 &lt;vishnu93> has joined #ccm
14:24 &lt;sdumitriu> Well, contact Quaid for his projects, or join #phenotips for that kind of projects
14:25 &lt;nclandrei> so if I've already sent Mr. Morris an email, should I hop on the other channel, the Phenotips one? (-:
14:25 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes, if you really like the idea
14:25 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi vishnu93, how can I help you?
14:41 &lt;vishnu93> Hi
14:42 &lt;vishnu93> I'm a fourth year student pursuing B.E. Computer Science
14:42 &lt;vishnu93> I was interested in the Machine Learning Project for Modeling Tumors
14:43 &lt;vishnu93> I've worked on projects on Machine Learning, for which I used python's scikit learn
14:44 &lt;vishnu93> I've contacted Mr. Morris about the idea
14:45 &lt;sdumitriu> OK, I guess you should wait for an answer from him
14:45 &lt;vishnu93> Yeah
14:45 &lt;vishnu93> Thanks :)
22:01 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.ccmArchive20140225</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>d1231378-8769-48cb-bab9-046ea87713cd</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>ccm</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>