<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>ccmArchive20140317</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.sdumitriu</creator>
  <creationDate>1395033310000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.sdumitriu</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.sdumitriu</contentAuthor>
  <date>1395114735000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1395114735000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.177</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #ccm on 17 March 2014</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
01:17 &lt;sdumitriu1> has joined #ccm
08:23 &lt;winter_flower> has joined #ccm
10:46 &lt;ruthgrace_> has joined #ccm
10:50 &lt;ruthgrace_> Hello. I am a 4th year student at the University of Western Ontario, studying for a Bachelor of Medical Science, in the Honors Spec Computational Biochemistry module. I am interested in applying for Google Summer of Code.
10:51 &lt;ruthgrace_> The two projects that I think I would be most suited for are the MedSavant pathway analysis app and the project to extend Phenotips to use ICD-10 ontology
10:51 &lt;ruthgrace_> Do you already have students in mind for this project?
10:52 &lt;ruthgrace_> Or the MedSavant one?
10:52 &lt;ruthgrace_> Thanks in advance.
10:58 &lt;ruthgrace_> I will email Asha about the MedSavant pathway analysis project. Thank you.
11:36 &lt;s37syed> has joined #ccm
11:36 &lt;s37syed> hello everyone!
11:40 &lt;s37syed> I had a question in regards to developing the MedSavant BigData back end. I have lots of experience with some DB, only read up on MapReduce. I definitely have experience with some Data Mining techniques, and would like to apply. Would I still be eligble even though I don't have any formal experience with Hadoop MapReduce?
11:41 &lt;s37syed> I know there's only four days left as well, and my submission will probably be really last minute, unfortunately education does have its flaws. =P
12:08 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #ccm
12:09 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi ruthgrace_
12:09 &lt;ruthgrace_> hello
12:10 &lt;sdumitriu> Both projects are still open
12:10 &lt;ruthgrace_> Thank you. I am more interested in the pathway analysis app than the ontology one. Do you think it is worth applying to both?
12:11 &lt;sdumitriu> So yes, email Asha for the Pathways project
12:11 &lt;sdumitriu> Well, it depends
12:11 &lt;ruthgrace_> I've emailed Asha and the CCM mentors email already.
12:11 &lt;ruthgrace_> Do you know what my chances of getting the position are?
12:12 &lt;ruthgrace_> I noticed that Sick Kids is only planning on taking 2-4 students.
12:12 &lt;sdumitriu> The more projects you apply to, the better your chances of being selected for one of them
12:12 &lt;sdumitriu> On the other hand, the more you spread out, the lower the quality of each application
12:12 &lt;ruthgrace_> Thanks. Would trying to patch a small bug in MedSavant greatly increase my chances?
12:13 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
12:13 &lt;ruthgrace_> And do you know how many students have contacted CCM regarding a Google Summer of Code project?
12:13 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, let me check
12:14 &lt;sdumitriu> Around 40 that I know of
12:14 &lt;ruthgrace_> Wow! Have any of them tried to patch anything in MedSavant?
12:14 &lt;sdumitriu> Not yet
12:15 &lt;ruthgrace_> Okay. I will try to be the first. Thank you very much! I appreciate it.
12:15 &lt;sdumitriu> You're welcome
13:12 &lt;SayAsh> has joined #ccm
17:09 &lt;pritham> has joined #ccm
17:11 &lt;pritham> Hi!
17:13 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi pritham
17:15 &lt;pritham> I was having a little trouble setting up the PhenoTips project on my computer.
17:15 &lt;pritham> When I run "mvn install", I'm getting: [ERROR] Failed to execute goal org.codehaus.mojo:clirr-maven-plugin:2.5:check (c lirr-check) on project patient-data-api: There were 2 errors. -> [Help 1] org.apache.maven.lifecycle.LifecycleExecutionException: Failed to execute goal o rg.codehaus.mojo:clirr-maven-plugin:2.5:check (clirr-check) on project patient-d ata-api: There were 2 errors.
17:20 &lt;tweety098> has joined #ccm
17:29 &lt;sdumitriu> pritham: Did you make any changes, or is that the official code?
17:33 &lt;pritham> Nope. No changes yet. That was the official code.
17:34 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, that error shouldn't be there...
17:34 &lt;sdumitriu> Can you pastebin the whole log?
17:36 &lt;pritham> Definitely. One moment.
17:45 &lt;pritham> http://pastebin.com/gkEtyswa
17:51 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, weird, GitHub might have made a bad merge
18:05 &lt;sdumitriu> pritham: What version of Maven are you using?
18:05 &lt;sdumitriu> mvn -version
18:11 &lt;pritham> has joined #ccm
18:12 &lt;sdumitriu> pritham: What version of Maven are you using?
18:12 &lt;sdumitriu> mvn -version
18:12 &lt;pritham> 3.2.1
18:13 &lt;sdumitriu> I've just committed a change that might fix it, but you should use Maven 3.0.x anyway, since other things will fail with a different version
18:22 &lt;ruthgrace_> sdumitriu: should we be using Maven 3.0.x for MedSavant too?
18:22 &lt;sdumitriu> No
18:22 &lt;sdumitriu> That should work with newer versions
18:22 &lt;ruthgrace_> Perfect! Thanks.
20:25 &lt;ruthgrace> has joined #ccm
20:53 &lt;ruthgrace> Hello, what is the best way to install the MedSavant client on linux mint?
20:53 &lt;ruthgrace> I keep getting a null pointer exception
20:54 &lt;sdumitriu> What did you try?
20:55 &lt;ruthgrace> I mvn packaged the client and tried to run the .jar . I think I need the server, too, though
20:55 &lt;ruthgrace> Is that correct?
20:55 &lt;sdumitriu> It depends
20:55 &lt;ruthgrace> I also tried packaging the installer and running that, with the same null pointer exception
20:55 &lt;sdumitriu> You need _a_ server to connect to
20:56 &lt;sdumitriu> So most likely you do need to have the server running locally
20:56 &lt;ruthgrace> Okay. Thank you.
20:57 &lt;sdumitriu> But when do you get the exception?
20:57 &lt;sdumitriu&gt; Do you get to the login screen, or is it before that?
20:57 &lt;ruthgrace> Before that.
20:57 &lt;ruthgrace> And when I click the option to report the error there is another error.
20:58 &lt;ruthgrace> Should running the server be a simple matter of running mvn install in the MedSavantServerEngine directory and then running the resulting .jar?
21:00 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes, except that you also need to install http://www.infobright.org/ and start it
21:00 &lt;sdumitriu> Since that's the DB that MedSavant uses
21:00 &lt;ruthgrace> Ah, thank you.
21:02 &lt;sdumitriu> Well, if you don't get to the login screen, then something else is wrong
21:02 &lt;sdumitriu> Can you pastebin the stack trace?
21:06 &lt;ruthgrace> Sure. One second.
21:10 &lt;ruthgrace> http://pastebin.com/HvHy9fWs
21:11 &lt;ruthgrace> Right at the point where it says '5 more ..." I clicked Report in the null pointer exception dialog, and got another error.
21:13 &lt;ruthgrace> So the first error says Error, null, cause: null pointer exception, and after I click Report Issue, the second error says Could not initialize class org.ut.biolab.medsavant.client.view.util.ViewUtil
21:13 &lt;ruthgrace> and if I press Report Issue again, the second error reoccurs
21:13 &lt;ruthgrace> I packaged it this type by typing 'mvn install'
21:14 &lt;ruthgrace> in the MedSavantClient directory
21:15 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, that looks like a bug
21:15 &lt;ruthgrace> I am running Maven 3.0.4, with Java version 1.7.0_25
21:15 &lt;sdumitriu> Marc recently made some changes to the fonts
21:16 &lt;ruthgrace> Should I try it on a windows machine instead?
21:16 &lt;sdumitriu> No
21:16 &lt;ruthgrace> Do you think that would make a difference?
21:16 &lt;ruthgrace> Okay.
21:17 &lt;ruthgrace> Is it correct that once the bug is fixed, I can run the client by installing ICE, running the MedSavantServerEngine .jar, and then running the MedSavantClient .jar ?
21:18 &lt;sdumitriu> Yep, I got the same error
21:18 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes, that is correct
21:18 &lt;sdumitriu> You could prove your skills by fixing this bug
21:19 &lt;ruthgrace> Haha, alright. How long will you  be here for?
21:20 &lt;ruthgrace> I will do my best. :)
21:21 &lt;sdumitriu> I don't know, I'll be here for a while
21:21 &lt;ruthgrace> Thanks again. I'm sure I will have more questions later.
21:32 &lt;ruthgrace> Do you have an SMTP host, user name, password, etc. for the log4j appender?
21:33 &lt;ruthgrace> When I run the MedSavantServerEngine .jar I get
21:33 &lt;ruthgrace> log4j:ERROR Could not find value for key log4j.appender.EMAIL
21:33 &lt;ruthgrace> log4j:ERROR Could not instantiate appender named "EMAIL".
21:34 &lt;sdumitriu&gt; That's another bug
21:35 &lt;ruthgrace> OK, I just took out the line that was using the EMAIL.
21:58 &lt;ruthgrace> What is the default directory at which MedSavant stores supporting files?
21:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Server or client?
21:59 &lt;ruthgrace> Server
21:59 &lt;ruthgrace> Is it just in src/main/resources?
21:59 &lt;ruthgrace> no, that can't be it - only the log4j.properties file is there
22:00 &lt;sdumitriu> No, by default it stores in the current directory, but you can create a configuration file for it
22:01 &lt;ruthgrace&gt; so inside the target directory?
22:01 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
22:01 &lt;ruthgrace> Okay. I think it's not initialized as anything. I'll find out in a bit.
22:02 &lt;sdumitriu> See distribution/medsavant-server-zip/src/main/resources/medsavant.properties
22:02 &lt;sdumitriu> You can copy that, change it, and use it with:
22:02 &lt;sdumitriu> java -jar medsavant-server-1.2-SNAPSHOT.jar -c medsavant.properties
22:03 &lt;ruthgrace> thanks! :)
22:44 &lt;ruthgrace> Hi, dumb question. I'm having trouble getting ICE set up. I've followed the install instructions here: https://www.infobright.org/index.php/ICE_Wiki/wiki-4/installation/Install-Guide-for-Linux/
22:44 &lt;ruthgrace> when I try to run /etc/init.d/mysqld-ib start  it says:
22:44 &lt;ruthgrace> Error - /etc/my-ib.cnf was not found! Please make sure Infobright installation completed and activated successfully.
22:45 &lt;ruthgrace> Would running /usr/local/infobright/postconfig.sh help?
22:45 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
22:46 &lt;ruthgrace> Do you know what the default installation directory is?
22:46 &lt;sdumitriu> But you must run it from the directory where that script is
22:47 &lt;ruthgrace> Ah. Thanks.
22:52 &lt;ruthgrace> Do you know why I am getting this error?
22:52 &lt;ruthgrace> com.mysql.jdbc.exceptions.jdbc4.MySQLNonTransientConnectionException: Could not create connection to database server. Attempted reconnect 3 times. Giving up.
22:53 &lt;ruthgrace> (from running the MedSavantServerEngine .jar after sucessfully starting the ICE database)
22:53 &lt;sdumitriu> Did you start the server?
22:53 &lt;sdumitriu> Make sure it is indeed running, run mysql-ib
22:54 &lt;ruthgrace> oh yes. that yields ERROR 2002 (HY000): Can't connect to local MySQL server through socket '/tmp/mysql-ib.sock' (2)
22:54 &lt;ruthgrace> When I run  /etc/init.d/mysqld-ib start
22:54 &lt;ruthgrace> it says:
22:55 &lt;ruthgrace> Starting MySQL ........ *
22:55 &lt;ruthgrace> and the asterisk is red
22:55 &lt;sdumitriu> So something failed
22:56 &lt;ruthgrace> Is there some sort of log file? To tell me what failed?
22:56 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
22:56 &lt;sdumitriu> Check in /etc/my-ib.cnf
22:56 &lt;sdumitriu> There should be a log-error setting
22:58 &lt;ruthgrace> the bh.err file that it points to seems to be empty
23:03 &lt;ruthgrace> Should I uncomment the #general_log=1 and #general_log_file=path-of-datadir/general_query.log, in /etc/my-ib.cnf  ?
23:06 &lt;sdumitriu> No, that's about actual SQL queries
23:08 &lt;ruthgrace> okay.
23:08 &lt;ruthgrace> I am at a loss as to what to try next. Do you have any suggestions?
23:09 &lt;sdumitriu> Did the postconfig script print any errors?
23:10 &lt;ruthgrace> Nope.
23:11 &lt;ruthgrace> it only printed this:
23:11 &lt;ruthgrace> http://pastebin.com/br1WfH6R
23:12 &lt;ruthgrace> (Infobright server activated)
23:13 &lt;sdumitriu> Check what's in /var/log/messages
23:15 &lt;ruthgrace> I don't seem to have messages in /var/log
23:15 &lt;ruthgrace> there is an empty mysql.err
23:17 &lt;ruthgrace> I just did sudo apt-get install mysql-server and sudo apt-get update, but they didn't help
23:17 &lt;ruthgrace> (i didn't have mysql-server before)
23:22 &lt;ruthgrace> I'm going to uncomment the lines recommended in post 2 of this thread: http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=1728570
23:22 &lt;ruthgrace> apparently that's how I can get a /var/log/messages
23:27 &lt;ruthgrace> hey, I have a /var/log/messages now
23:27 &lt;sdumitriu> Try to start mysqld-ib again
23:28 &lt;ruthgrace> it failed in the same way and all it says in my /var/log/messages is http://pastebin.com/hVyXJ4up
23:28 &lt;ruthgrace> the bh.err is empty as before.
23:33 &lt;ruthgrace> Any other suggestions?
23:42 &lt;ruthgrace> Should I make a pull request for changing the log4j.properties line from log4j.logger.org.ut.biolab.medsavant.db.variants.update=DEBUG, EMAIL to log4j.logger.org.ut.biolab.medsavant.db.variants.update=DEBUG to prevent that EMAIL error?
23:43 &lt;sdumitriu> I'm not sure
23:43 &lt;sdumitriu> There used to be a definition for the EMAIL logger, but Marc removed it
23:43 &lt;sdumitriu> Not sure why
23:43 &lt;sdumitriu> You can make a pull request and ask for feedback
23:44 &lt;ruthgrace> Sure
23:44 &lt;ruthgrace> Should I try to find someone at infobright to help me get the database server working?
23:48 &lt;sdumitriu> Yep
23:52 &lt;ruthgrace> Is this the right place to do that: https://www.infobright.org/forums/sendmessage.php
23:52 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.ccmArchive20140317</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>c61b4592-e9d8-4390-8ea1-cb12940b567d</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>ccm</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>