<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>medsavantArchive20130617</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.Admin</creator>
  <creationDate>1371446574000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.Admin</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.Admin</contentAuthor>
  <date>1371509086000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1371509086000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.88</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #medsavant on 17 June 2013</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;sdumitriu> has joined #medsavant
09:29 &lt;sdumitriu1> has joined #medsavant
17:12 &lt;bvancea> has joined #medsavant
17:14 &lt;sdumitriu> Hey bvancea
17:15 &lt;bvancea> hello sdumitriu :)
17:15 &lt;bvancea> what's up?
17:16 &lt;sdumitriu> SCO
17:16 &lt;bvancea> what is SCO?
17:16 &lt;sdumitriu> The dead company that's been insisting for the past 20 years that it owns Linux
17:17 &lt;bvancea> =)))))
17:17 &lt;sdumitriu> http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCO-Linux_controversies
17:19 &lt;bvancea> haha
17:19 &lt;bvancea> although
17:19 &lt;bvancea> why do these companies claim ownership over Linux?
17:19 &lt;sdumitriu> Which ones?
17:19 &lt;sdumitriu> SCO?
17:19 &lt;bvancea> Red Hat, Novell, IBM
17:20 &lt;bvancea> and SCO
17:20 &lt;sdumitriu> Well, they don't
17:20 &lt;sdumitriu> SCO claims that it owns a UNIX variant, and that some Linux code copied code from that variant
17:20 &lt;sdumitriu> In truth the UNIX variant they got was just the right to use, not the full copyright
17:20 &lt;bvancea> yeah, you're right
17:21 &lt;bvancea> I miss-read the first time
17:21 &lt;bvancea> even so, there was so much development on the linux kernel
17:21 &lt;sdumitriu> And the few lines of code that were similar both in Linux and in their UNIX was coming from an earlier kernel that is in the public domain
17:21 &lt;sdumitriu> So they both copied from the same (open) source
17:21 &lt;bvancea> haha
17:22 &lt;sdumitriu> Well, that's the public part
17:23 &lt;sdumitriu> The secret is that SCO is being funded by enemies of Linux to spread FUD about Linux
17:23 &lt;sdumitriu> Of course, there's no real proof for that
17:23 &lt;bvancea> interesting
17:23 &lt;bvancea> well, tbh, Linux grew so much these last few years
17:24 &lt;bvancea> I think it's really hard to make people lose their interest
17:24 &lt;sdumitriu> SCO didn't produce anything, it went bankrupt a few times, and all it lives on is the hope that at some point they're going to win this trial and get a few billions back from IBM, RedHat and Novell
17:24 &lt;sdumitriu> True
17:24 &lt;sdumitriu> But MS never stops
17:24 &lt;bvancea> so SCO is like those twins that keep suing Zuckerberg
17:24 &lt;sdumitriu> Yeah, something like that
17:25 &lt;bvancea> yeah, MS has some really ugly negative publicity tactics
17:25 &lt;bvancea> like the Scroogled campain
17:25 &lt;sdumitriu> Get The Facts
17:26 &lt;sdumitriu> Or the fact that GMail is evil because it's reading your email, when in fact at some point the HotMail terms of use stated that MS owns your emails and can do whatever with it, not you
17:27 &lt;sdumitriu> Anyway, the coding period is officially started
17:27 &lt;sdumitriu> What are your plans for this week?
17:27 &lt;bvancea> yeah :D
17:27 &lt;bvancea> I'm writing my status email now :)
17:28 &lt;bvancea> I'm thinking I could keep indexing variants
17:28 &lt;bvancea> and continue testing
17:28 &lt;bvancea> and in parallel check to see how another entity can be indexed
17:28 &lt;bvancea> or refactor my code
17:29 &lt;bvancea> not sure if you have something in mind that I could do
17:31 &lt;bvancea> also, would it be ok if we set some sort of a milestone for the end of the first part of the coding period?
17:31 &lt;sdumitriu> Sure
17:32 &lt;sdumitriu> We'll discuss that at the call on Thursday
17:32 &lt;sdumitriu> (thursday was it?)
17:32 &lt;bvancea> ah, cool
17:32 &lt;bvancea> I'm pretty sure its thursday
17:32 &lt;bvancea> we didn't set a time for it yet
17:35 &lt;bvancea> okay so, what should I set as a target for this week? a schema for the genes or some refactoring?
17:36 &lt;bvancea> eh, I think both could be viable
17:37 &lt;bvancea> I'll prepare some sort of a weekly plan for the first part of the coding then. So we can have it as a base for discussion on Thursday
17:38 &lt;sdumitriu> I'd say refactoring
17:38 &lt;bvancea> hmm
17:38 &lt;bvancea> okay
17:40 &lt;bvancea> also, how should we do about the code reviews?
17:41 &lt;bvancea> I mean, if the features aren't yet integrated in medsavant
17:41 &lt;bvancea> I'm guessing pull requests aren't quite ok for that
17:44 &lt;sdumitriu> Well, there are two ways
17:45 &lt;sdumitriu> One is to grant you commit access to the official repo, and you commit in a branch
17:46 &lt;sdumitriu> The second is to commit on your fork and to make pull requests into a feature branch whenever you're in a stable state
17:46 &lt;sdumitriu> I think the first one is OK, since there aren't that many committers on MedSavant to be picky
17:46 &lt;bvancea> well, I've commited twice on my fork so far
17:47 &lt;bvancea> and I'm still refactoring some code, but it seems to me it'll be increasingly harder for you to review
17:47 &lt;bvancea> if I have many commits
17:57 &lt;sdumitriu> The more, the better
17:57 &lt;sdumitriu> Many and small
17:57 &lt;bvancea> and, I see
17:57 &lt;bvancea> ok
17:58 &lt;bvancea> btw, have you worked a lot with Solr clusters?
17:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Nope
17:58 &lt;bvancea> ;))
17:58 &lt;bvancea> I've only made a real one for my diploma project
17:59 &lt;bvancea> and indexing seems to get slower
17:59 &lt;bvancea> the bigger the cluster
18:02 &lt;bvancea> I watched a few videos about SolrCloud this weekend
18:02 &lt;bvancea> and I was thinking that maybe we could try sending documents to more nodes, in parallel
18:03 &lt;bvancea> but that might confuze the cluster and make it even slower
18:44 &lt;bvancea> good night</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.medsavantArchive20130617</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>023f1671-f1d2-466b-a79b-380ee0946799</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>medsavant</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>