<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>phenotipsArchive20140225</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.sdumitriu</creator>
  <creationDate>1393310214000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.sdumitriu</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.sdumitriu</contentAuthor>
  <date>1393384404000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1393384404000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.278</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #phenotips on 25 February 2014</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
01:37 &lt;gauravsaini03> Hello
01:38 &lt;qwebirc19402> has quit
01:42 &lt;gauravsaini03> has quit
01:50 &lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
01:50 &lt;gauravsaini03> Hello
01:56 &lt;gauravsaini03> has quit
03:14 &lt;qwebirc71202> has quit
03:27 &lt;anishshah101____> has joined #phenotips
03:29 &lt;marta__1> has joined #phenotips
03:30 &lt;marta__> has quit
05:08 &lt;raghav> has quit
05:58 &lt;raghav> has quit
06:19 &lt;raghav> has quit
08:08 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #phenotips
08:08 &lt;anishshah101____> has quit
08:13 &lt;marta__1> has quit
08:13 &lt;sdumitriu> has quit
08:14 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #phenotips
08:25 &lt;sdumitriu> has quit
08:28 &lt;marta__> has joined #phenotips
08:31 &lt;nclandrei_> has quit
08:40 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #phenotips
09:01 &lt;sdumitriu> has quit
09:19 &lt;allasm> has quit
09:19 &lt;allasm> has joined #phenotips
09:42 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
09:43 &lt;marta__1> has joined #phenotips
09:45 &lt;marta__> has quit
10:29 &lt;nclandrei_> has quit
10:30 &lt;nclandrei__> has quit
10:50 &lt;sdumitriu_[away]&gt; is now known as &lt;sdumitriu>
10:52 &lt;marta__> has joined #phenotips
10:54 &lt;marta__1> has quit
11:22 &lt;akats> remember when I made that weird build a long time ago, with "overlays" folder popping outside of "target" folder? Well its legacy lives on in the form of "overlays" being a line in .gitignore.
11:22 &lt;marta__> has quit
11:22 &lt;akats> Can I remove it?
11:22 &lt;marta__> has joined #phenotips
11:23 &lt;sdumitriu> If you're sure it won't happen again, yes
11:23 &lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
11:24 &lt;gauravsaini03> Hello
11:24 &lt;akats> I am not, but if that lines stays it needs to be modified, because I can't commit files in distribution/war/overlays
11:24 &lt;akats> Hello
11:25 &lt;gauravsaini03> I am student willing to contribute with GSOC this year.
11:27 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi gauravsaini03
11:28 &lt;gauravsaini03> I have followed all the instruction sent by my  mentor.
11:28 &lt;marta__> has quit
11:29 &lt;gauravsaini03> Just want to know what next I have to do for getting selecting for the project I selected.
11:30 &lt;gauravsaini03> I have build the software and read dev and user docs.
11:30 &lt;gauravsaini03> hello
11:30 &lt;gauravsaini03> I am done with the build and have read dev and user guide.
11:31 &lt;gauravsaini03> During the startup on running startup.sh
11:31 &lt;gauravsaini03> I got this error
11:32 &lt;gauravsaini03>  [main] ERROR o.x.s.s.i.RemoteSolrInstance   - Failed to generate the remote server's configuration.
11:32 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes, that's a known bug that is going to go away in a few days, it's "normal"
11:33 &lt;sdumitriu> So, did you get to understand a bit better what PhenoTips does?
11:36 &lt;gauravsaini03> yes
11:37 &lt;gauravsaini03> I was getting error during build
11:37 &lt;gauravsaini03> but I managed to get it solved
11:37 &lt;gauravsaini03> something in my mvn setting.xml has problem
11:38 &lt;gauravsaini03> Just saw, Actually you replied to my mail. :)
11:38 &lt;gauravsaini03> Just want to know what is the default login/password ?
11:41 &lt;sdumitriu> u=Admin / p=admin
11:41 &lt;sdumitriu> Admin is case sensitive
11:43 &lt;gauravsaini03> thanks
11:43 &lt;akats> has quit
11:44 &lt;gauravsaini03> So, What should be my next step ?
11:52 &lt;gauravsaini03> Also, I want to know the zip file I extracted after building the code. Do I have to change in that only or I have to change in main project and build it again ?
11:53 &lt;gauravsaini03> Also, when running in jetty server is it hot-deployed ? So I can change in vm files to see that changes ?
11:55 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: Hold on a bit, talking with someone else
11:56 &lt;gauravsaini03> ok.
12:01 &lt;root_l> has joined #phenotips
12:02 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: Well, the zip file is just the output
12:02 &lt;sdumitriu> When you change things there, they don't go back into the sources
12:02 &lt;root_l> am around now from other channel
12:02 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
12:03 &lt;root_l> so i earlier asked for more tips about my interests
12:03 &lt;sdumitriu> So, you can modify the running code in there, since it's faster to see the results (and for most files you don't need to restart the server), but all the changes will be lost if you don't commit them back into the sources
12:03 &lt;sdumitriu> allasm: root_l wants to know about the pedigree
12:04 &lt;gauravsaini03> Also, I want to know what exactly is the templating system of phenotips ?
12:04 &lt;gauravsaini03> Is there jsp, freemarker or velocity ?
12:05 &lt;root_l> guaravsaini03 seems to be looking for similar tips too
12:05 &lt;gauravsaini03> As I just saw db.srcipts having the code I searched for !
12:07 &lt;gauravsaini03> Where I can see the template code ?
12:07 &lt;sosna> has quit
12:09 &lt;akats> We mainly use velocity if that is what you are asking
12:09 &lt;akats> Usually we create a document in xwiki and then write the velocity code directly in the xwiki editor
12:11 &lt;akats> Here's a good link http://platform.xwiki.org/xwiki/bin/view/DevGuide/Scripting
12:11 &lt;akats> The bindings section is especially useful
12:12 &lt;sdumitriu> PhenoTips is built on top of a wiki, you edit the code in the browser
12:13 &lt;sdumitriu> Never edit the database script file
12:13 &lt;gauravsaini03> ok.
12:14 &lt;sdumitriu> Each document comes from an .xml file in the sources, it gets built into a hsqldb database (the .script file), and then you can access it from the browser
12:14 &lt;gauravsaini03> Let me look into it.
12:14 &lt;rays2pix> has quit
12:14 &lt;sdumitriu> When you're done editing the document, you can export it as a .xar file, which is actually just a .zip file with the .xml source in it
12:15 &lt;sdumitriu> You can then copy that xml back into the sources
12:15 &lt;gauravsaini03> ok. Is there any doc available for editing and how to commit back the code with the xml ?
12:16 &lt;sdumitriu> The problem is that it will be messier, so you have to run "mvn xar:format" from the root directory of that module (the one with a pom.xml file and the src) to reformat it
12:16 &lt;gauravsaini03> I am confused that if I edit directly in wiki so how I can commit it ?
12:16 &lt;sdumitriu> There is now: http://phenotips.org/IRC/phenotipsArchive20140225
12:17 &lt;sdumitriu> As I said, export as .xar, unzip it, copy the .xml back in the right place in the sources, run mvn xar:format, git add &amp;&amp; git commit
12:17 &lt;gauravsaini03> ok great. I got it. :)
12:18 &lt;gauravsaini03> I will get into it and do some changes., then will work on the issues in the issue tracker to be more familiar with phenotips
12:18 &lt;gauravsaini03> Thanks &lt;sdumitriu>
12:20 &lt;sdumitriu> You're welcome
12:20 &lt;root_l> with phenotips, where can i get source code?
12:20 &lt;root_l> if any already exists
12:21 &lt;sdumitriu> root_l: Did you check http://phenotips.org ?
12:21 &lt;allasm> hi root_l, sdumitriutold me you may be interested in the new mobile pedigree UI project?
12:21 &lt;sdumitriu> There should be plenty of links to the code
12:21 &lt;root_l> i mean for mobile platform deployment
12:21 &lt;sdumitriu> Oh, there's no specific code for mobile UI
12:21 &lt;root_l> allasm:yeah
12:22 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: ok i see
12:22 &lt;gauravsaini03> allasm : I am also interested in this project (Mobile Web interface for PhenoTips) for GSOC
12:22 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: so if am in i will have to design that for GSOC
12:22 &lt;allasm> well, there is no specificaly mobile code as of yet. What I would do to get an idea of what needs to be done is the following:
12:23 &lt;root_l> allasm:ok listening
12:23 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: There are two projects, UI for the main PhenoTips, and UI for the Pedigree feature of PhenoTips
12:23 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: yeah , i have seen it on the ideas page
12:24 &lt;gauravsaini03> sdumitriu: ok thanks. Just saw the ideas page again
12:25 &lt;root_l> sdumitriu: ammostly interested in the entire phenotips UI/UX
12:27 &lt;allasm> 1) install a copy of phenotips from phenotips.org (see build and instlal instructions there, as well as defaultadministrative login/password). Then create a new patient (there is a link form the "home" page), open/edit the patient, go to the "family history" section and there will be  a"create new pedigree" button. There you can see our existing javascript-based UI
12:28 &lt;root_l> allasm: got it. am on it now
12:28 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: Intellijidea kills hardlinks. :)
12:28 &lt;allasm> 2) to browse the UI code check our github: https://github.com/phenotips/phenotips, more specifically here: https://github.com/phenotips/phenotips/tree/master/pedigree/src/main/resources/pedigree
12:28 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: Why?!
12:29 &lt;allasm> (there is a log of code, start looking form pedigree.js) In the phwork
12:30 &lt;allasm> subdirectory there is some code which computes the layout of pedigrees before they are drawn, yoou will likely have to reuse that as the "back end" for the mobile UI as well (or a port of that if javascript won't work - that can be discussed separately)
12:31 &lt;allasm> ...and ask any questions here :)
12:31 &lt;sdumitriu> allasm: Speaking of phwork, shouldn't that directory be renamed or something?
12:35 &lt;allasm> definitely. I just noticed the name myself while giving out the links!
12:36 &lt;gauravsaini03> allasm: Can you give me idea, How I should go for Mobile web Interface ? As, I think we should use bootstrap framework for optimizing phenotips for mobile and tablets
12:36 &lt;gauravsaini03> As bootstrap support best responsiveness and top used css framework nowadays
12:37 &lt;root_l> gauravsaini03 : seems like an option
12:45 &lt;aw1231> has joined #phenotips
12:49 &lt;allasm> to be honest, I have no strong preferences (yet) as to how mobile UI should be implemented - to be honest, I'm not an expert on UIs, and know just about as much about what is/are the best framewroks/tooks for that as anyone generally interested in the topic. I will check what bootstrap has to offer right now and we can talk about it in a few days.meanwhile, aAny arguments for/against any tools/libraries are welcome!
12:55 &lt;allasm> (I've seen/played a bit with jQuery mobile and sencha touch, can't say I particularly liked them, but the results were good. On the desktop, we use raphaelJS, as we need to draw a lot of custom shapes. Again, it is nice nbiut has its drawbacks. If you think bootstrap can do the job best - sure, just provide some arguments. And make sure you first check the existing pedigrees so that you know what needs to be done/drawn in the first place :)
12:57 &lt;root_l> allasm: i think JQuery mobile too is good.
12:58 &lt;root_l> allasm: after downloading and viewing the mobile source i will run a simulation and propose what i think to be more appropriate according to me
12:59 &lt;allasm> this (http://phenotips.org/download/PhenoTips/FeaturePreview/Pedigree-example.png) screenshot is a good starting point of what kind of stuff we want ot have as a result (it is  abit ugly aroudn the corners and outdated, but gives a good idea). The desktop UI definitely doe snto work for mobile, we probably want to let th eusers draw circles and squares with their fingers, etc., but, once drawn, the result should look similarly
12:59 &lt;gauravsaini03> allasm: If we use JQM/sencha touch  then we have to write some kind of filter that will render different template (mobile and desktop) based on the device.
13:00 &lt;gauravsaini03> With bootstrap and responsive design
13:00 &lt;gauravsaini03> the same can layout can be used for multiple devices and screens.
13:00 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: That's a bad idea in general
13:00 &lt;root_l> gauravsaini03 : well it surely is the work to be done anyway
13:00 &lt;sdumitriu> The same site should work on desktops and tablets
13:01 &lt;root_l> i personally find JQuery Mobile more flexible
13:01 &lt;gauravsaini03> Yes, that is what I am proposing with Bootstrap
13:01 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: Is it unwanted to introduce more javascript libraries?
13:01 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: Define more
13:02 &lt;allasm> well, as much as having one unified UI is a good idea, we are very likely to have to keep supporting two versions, as on the desktop with a mouse you can do some stuff much easier and faster one way, while on the mibile with touchscreen soethign totally different may make more sense (where some options may be more cumbersome to do that on the desktop, while others may come more naturally). Again, no strong opinions there, but keep in mind that the desktop
13:02 &lt;allasm> version of the UI would have to run on some older dcompouters which definitely ownt have touch, and used by some older people (doctors) who may be used the mouse ways. Again, if somethign new works for both cases - great!
13:02 &lt;gauravsaini03> With JQM and sencha we will have this problem of maintaining two templates
13:03 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: I'm not sure but I think I can make my work neater with ko.js
13:04 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, a whole new framework isn't that easily accepted
13:06 &lt;allasm> two is worse than one of course. If one framework can nicely do both touch and click and draw nice shapes - perfect
13:06 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: ok
13:07 &lt;root_l> allasm: i think its even better that way
13:08 &lt;aw1231> has quit
13:09 &lt;allasm> in any case, user input is the main problem - we
13:10 &lt;sdumitriu> Right
13:11 &lt;allasm> the current design is already kind of "responsive" in the sense that it can probably be used on modern mobiles just fine in terms of the size/layoout etfc. it is the input that does not work well (of course, we can always improve the layout too)
13:11 &lt;sdumitriu> It's not as much about how to *show* the data, but how to let users easily enter it
13:11 &lt;sdumitriu> That's the main purpose of PhenoTips, collecting patient data
13:18 &lt;gauravsaini03> has quit
13:18 &lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
13:19 &lt;gauravsaini03> Let me give you some screenshot example of both responsive and non-responsive for better understanding my point.
13:22 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: Does the "new" version of phenotips require a registration [active install] to work properly?
13:22 &lt;root_l> allasm: what about the "Pathway analysis app for MedSavant"? what is the expected outcome of the project?
13:23 &lt;root_l> allasm: what is MedSavant anyway? because there is no further info about this on the ideas page
13:29 &lt;gauravsaini03> This is the screenshot from moile of phenotips login page. https://www.dropbox.com/s/qquidm06ivw5rsn/Screenshot_2014-02-25-23-50-28.png
13:29 &lt;gauravsaini03> User have to zoom to fill the details
13:30 &lt;gauravsaini03> Other side this is a contactup page of a responsive website https://www.dropbox.com/s/1zsvvj5z2p6hwn4/Screenshot_2014-02-25-23-54-25.png
13:31 &lt;gauravsaini03> allasm: So, that is the main difference. I think responsiveness will definitely solve the problem of user input in mobile/tablets.
13:46 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: http://modern.ie/en-us/virtualization-tools#downloads
13:46 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: It's a virtual machine
13:46 &lt;allasm> root_l: medsavant is a genomic browser - http://medsavant.org/. i'm not directly affiliated with the project, and this particular chat room is no tht ebest place to ask Medsavant questions as few medsavant devs are here. I think your best option is to email, unless sdumitriu has a better suggestion
13:47 &lt;sdumitriu> root_l: Yes, MedSavant is a different project, and I've tried really hard to make their devs have a common chatroom without success
13:47 &lt;sdumitriu> Email is the best option
13:48 &lt;akats> yup but you don't need vine
13:48 &lt;akats> wine*
13:48 &lt;allasm> gauravsaini03: I know what you are talking about. Phenotips project in general may have some areas which can be more "responsive", but we don't think the pedigree component is a) affected, it already works fine on most resolutions and b) scaling it solves user input problems.
13:49 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: Heh, that's actually a nice initiative from Microsoft
13:50 &lt;akats> It's struggling not to go the way of the dinosaurs.
13:50 &lt;allasm> Play with it on a live install to get a feel of how it works.in particular, even if user input is "ok-ish", we think a specifically mobile extension can be much better, e.g. create new nodes by drawing circles and squares with a finger (just as an example, we never tried so this particular one may not work :). At the same time with  amouse it makes more sense and is more natural to click a corresponding button, e.g. not sure most of people will be able to
13:50 &lt;allasm> draw a circle clearly distinguishable form a square with a mouse
13:50 &lt;sdumitriu> WYSIWYG documents are terrible... You get numbered lists like 1, 3, 3, 4, 5...
13:51 &lt;sdumitriu> Doesn't anybody check these documents? They're official licenses, so legal documents
13:51 &lt;allasm> heh. i thikn numbers are just fo rhumans as there must be a legal sentence similar in meaning to "all of the following should be true", no matter the numbers. But indeed funny
13:52 &lt;gauravsaini03> allasm: ok. Actually I did not saw pedigree component. If it's already good on most resolution, then I can work on rest web interface. As the project I am planning to work this summer is (Mobile Web interface for PhenoTips).
13:54 &lt;allasm> gauravsaini03: sure, that is a different story. As a final note, the entire prject is (IMHO) unlikely to be used on mobile phones, a tablet is much more likely. At the same time a lot of offices may have older monitors, e.g. 19" 1280x1024, i.e. a resolution lower than most tablets have. So for pedigree or not, the project is not purely about tiny resolution and responsive design. Let sdumitru correct me if I'm wrong
13:54 &lt;sdumitriu> You're right
13:55 &lt;sdumitriu> Tablets are the main "mobile" target
13:55 &lt;sdumitriu> And bigger touchscreen devices
13:57 &lt;gauravsaini03> allasm: So, Is this project still open to work in GSOC ? (Mobile Web interface for PhenoTips)
13:57 &lt;allasm> (of course, thesame inpiut controls dispolayed on a 10" screen and a 19" screen do not provide the sam euse rexperience, so even if everything fit some kind of responsive refactoring is likley in order)
13:58 &lt;allasm> as far as i know - yes :) But i f anything sdumitru is the person in the know
14:02 &lt;gauravsaini03> sdumitriu: What you say ?
14:04 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: Yes, it's a valid project
14:04 &lt;gauravsaini03> thanks :)
14:05 &lt;gauravsaini03> So, I what should be my next step to get selected for this project in GSOC ?
14:05 &lt;gauravsaini03> I am done with set up and read dev and user guide.
14:06 &lt;sosna> has joined #phenotips
14:07 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: It's better not to mention so often "getting selected"
14:08 &lt;sdumitriu> Your goal should be to learn :)
14:08 &lt;gauravsaini03> sdumitriu: Sorry, Might be overexicted about this.
14:09 &lt;gauravsaini03> Yes, I am here to learn :) and will give my best to learn as much as possible.
14:09 &lt;gauravsaini03> I will start with some initial issues in issue tracker.
14:10 &lt;gauravsaini03> Is this right way to go ? or anything else I have missed ?
14:10 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
14:10 &lt;sdumitriu> We prefer students that take initiative
14:11 &lt;sdumitriu> So don't ask what to do too often, find something to do and ask for help when stuck at something specific
14:11 &lt;gauravsaini03> sdumitriu: yes, I understand. thanks for all info.
14:12 &lt;sdumitriu> You're welcome
14:22 &lt;vishnu93> has joined #phenotips
14:26 &lt;sosna> has quit
14:28 &lt;nclandrei__> has joined #phenotips
14:28 &lt;nclandrei__> I have commuted! hi everyone
14:29 &lt;mcupak> has quit
14:29 &lt;nclandrei__> so, I would be very interested in the following project for Google Summer of Code: Multiple visits support in PhenoTips
14:31 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: Can you help out nclandrei__ with a few pointers, now that you know what needs to be done?
14:31 &lt;gauravsaini03> sdumitriu: yes ofcourse
14:32 &lt;gauravsaini03> nclandrei__ : To get started please read the devResource at http://phenotips.org/DeveloperResources/
14:33 &lt;gauravsaini03> Fist step is to build and run the project on your local machine
14:34 &lt;gauravsaini03> and explore it
14:36 &lt;nclandrei__> good, I have understood
14:36 &lt;gauravsaini03> :)
14:36 &lt;sdumitriu> Thank you gauravsaini03
14:36 &lt;gauravsaini03> sdumitriu: welcome
14:37 &lt;gauravsaini03> :)
14:37 &lt;nclandrei__> thank you very much
14:37 &lt;nclandrei__> after I've done that
14:37 &lt;nclandrei__> should I return for other steps/ advice?
14:37 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
14:38 &lt;nclandrei__> excellent
14:38 &lt;nclandrei__> thank you very much
14:38 &lt;sdumitriu> 1: Try to understand what PhenoTips does in general
14:38 &lt;sdumitriu> 2: Try to understand what the specific project (multiple visits) is supposed to do and get an idea of what would the end users get in the end
14:38 &lt;gauravsaini03> nclandrei__ : After you done with setup, try get in hand on some easy issues on issue tracker https://github.com/phenotips/phenotips/issues?labels=easy&amp;page=1&amp;state=open
14:42 &lt;nclandrei__> okay, good !
14:44 &lt;nclandrei__> I will keep with you in touch from now on, I'll keep staying here on the channel
14:44 &lt;nclandrei__> and if I have questions or ideas, I should come back
14:44 &lt;nclandrei__> thank you very much again !
14:44 &lt;sdumitriu> You're welcome
14:50 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: jquery can be accessed through require. took me long enough to figure that one out.
14:50 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
14:50 &lt;sdumitriu> There's a page on xwiki.org about that somewhere
14:52 &lt;sdumitriu> http://www.xwiki.org/xwiki/bin/view/ReleaseNotes/ReleaseNotesXWiki50M2#HJQueryinXWikiusingAMD2FRequire.js
14:54 &lt;akats> thanks
15:07 &lt;nclandrei__> I am going to sleep! thank you again for your help and I'll come back tomorrow with some feedback
15:07 &lt;nclandrei__> have a great day
15:07 &lt;nclandrei__> has quit
15:07 &lt;nclandrei> has quit
15:09 &lt;root_l> has quit
15:19 &lt;akats> has quit
15:48 &lt;vishnu93> has quit
15:48 &lt;gauravsaini03> has quit
15:56 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
16:25 &lt;sosna> has joined #phenotips
16:30 &lt;akats> has quit
16:32 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
16:32 &lt;akats> I fixed my internet!!!!
16:36 &lt;akats> has quit
16:37 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
16:54 &lt;sosna> has quit
17:58 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: Can you give me a hint where the code is that saves patient data when you click on the save button
17:59 &lt;sdumitriu> https://github.com/xwiki/xwiki-platform/blob/master/xwiki-platform-core/xwiki-platform-oldcore/src/main/java/com/xpn/xwiki/web/SaveAction.java
18:00 &lt;akats> thanks
18:00 &lt;sdumitriu> Don't thank me yet
18:05 &lt;akats> You're right. Let me ask you a better question. When you pick age of onset in the additional details of the phenotype, all the javascript code that gets executed seems to be related only to the visuals. There also seems to be no requests to an another xwiki page. How in the world is it saved?
18:06 &lt;sdumitriu> There is a request
18:45 &lt;akats> When you have a minute I wanted to ask you one last question before I go
19:08 &lt;akats> has quit
20:01 &lt;sdumitriu> is now known as &lt;sdumitriu_[Away]&gt;
22:01 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #phenotips
22:13 &lt;sdumitriu> has quit</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.phenotipsArchive20140225</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>f023ac00-4c7f-45f6-92bc-daeaec59d375</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>phenotips</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>