<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>phenotipsArchive20140320</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.sdumitriu</creator>
  <creationDate>1395297767000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.sdumitriu</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.sdumitriu</contentAuthor>
  <date>1395373998000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1395373998000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.157</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #phenotips on 20 March 2014</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;tian2992> has quit
03:30 &lt;ruthgrace> has quit
08:30 &lt;tian2992> has joined #phenotips
08:42 &lt;Shubham1> has quit
10:50 &lt;aw1231> has quit
12:34 &lt;Shubham> has quit
13:18 &lt;mcupak> has quit
13:40 &lt;qwebirc63957> has quit
14:24 &lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
14:25 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
14:25 &lt;akats> allasm: This might be useful http://www.modern.ie/en-us/virtualization-tools#downloads
14:28 &lt;gauravsaini03> has left #phenotips
15:34 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: So there is not way to use a hibernate class without having a configuration xml file for it?
15:35 &lt;sdumitriu> There is
15:35 &lt;sdumitriu> Why do you say that?
15:36 &lt;akats> I haven't been able to find it through google, and I keep getting the "Unknown entity" error
16:01 &lt;bvancea> has joined #phenotips
17:00 &lt;tian2992> sdumitriu: did you have a chance to check the IC predictor?
17:02 &lt;sdumitriu> Sorry tian2992, that meeting lasted longer, and after that another meeting started that lasted until close to midnight
17:02 &lt;sdumitriu> I'll check today
17:03 &lt;akats> has left #phenotips
17:15 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
17:21 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: I have a question for you. https://gist.github.com/soLEED/5c0f493ca9cc1721112e
17:25 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: Answered
17:27 &lt;akats> Thank you
17:42 &lt;mikola> has joined #phenotips
17:43 &lt;mikola> Hello everybody.
17:44 &lt;mikola> I am interested in building phenotips application and contributing to it. Can I post my questions here?
17:45 &lt;nairboon> has quit
17:50 &lt;sdumitriu> Hi mikola, sure
17:50 &lt;mikola> First of let me introduce myself.
17:51 &lt;mikola> My name is Mikalai Parafeniuk. I am a student from Belarus.
17:52 &lt;mikola> Right now I am trying to fix some beginner bugs in project. I need some basic advices about development process.
17:52 &lt;mikola> I have built the project and run it locally as it is described on github.
17:53 &lt;sdumitriu> Oh, right
17:53 &lt;sdumitriu> You asked to be assigned issues
17:53 &lt;mikola> Which ide should i use for the project, how can I speed up the build process?
17:53 &lt;sdumitriu> Forgot to answer, you don't need to be assigned explicitly, you can just work on those issues
17:53 &lt;mikola> Total time: 9:27.708s
17:53 &lt;mikola> [INFO] Finished at: Fri Mar 21 00:40:25 FET 2014
17:56 &lt;mikola> Don't worry it is not a problem. I have already started my work.
17:57 &lt;mikola> So, how can I improve my performance? I think that building project for 10 minutes every time is not effective.
17:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Is that time consisten between builds?
17:59 &lt;sdumitriu> The first build should indeed take a lot of time, but after that it should be lower
17:59 &lt;sdumitriu> There are several things you can do
17:59 &lt;sdumitriu> One is to build through an IDE
17:59 &lt;sdumitriu> We try to be IDE-agnostic, so you can use what you want
17:59 &lt;mikola> First build took about an hour to download all dependencies.
17:59 &lt;sdumitriu> But it would be better to use something with good support for Maven
18:00 &lt;sdumitriu> I prefer Eclipse, other prefer IntelliJ IDEA
18:00 &lt;sdumitriu> IDEA has better support for Maven
18:01 &lt;sdumitriu> The other thing is to not rebuild everything, but just the modules you're editing, then copy the jars you get in target/ to the running instance, and restart the server
18:01 &lt;sdumitriu> That works well for jar modules
18:02 &lt;sdumitriu> For ui modules, which end up in .xar, you can change the direction of the workflow and edit in the running instance, and export back the documents once you're happy with the results
18:02 &lt;mikola> There was nearly a day between builds.
18:02 &lt;sdumitriu> That's much faster than rebuilding the code
18:04 &lt;sdumitriu> Example editing in the browser: http://localhost:8080/bin/edit/PhenoTips/PatientSheetCode?editor=object
18:04 &lt;sdumitriu> You can quick save and refresh a patient profile to see the new code live
18:05 &lt;sdumitriu> Once you save and view, you'll see an Export -> XAR entry in the menu
18:05 &lt;sdumitriu> That is a .zip file with the source XML which you can copy back into the proper location in the source tree
18:05 &lt;sdumitriu> Run "mvn xar:format" in the module where that XML file is (the directory with a src/ and a pom.xml) to clean up the file
18:13 &lt;mikola> So the resources file which are the mix of xml and some language which starts with # shouldn't be edit manually? They can be edited directly in browser?
18:14 &lt;tian2992> sdumitriu: thanks :)
18:14 &lt;sdumitriu> They can be edited in the browser for faster results
18:14 &lt;sdumitriu> But you can edit them on disk if you want to
18:14 &lt;mikola> Cool %)
18:14 &lt;mikola> :)
18:15 &lt;sdumitriu> That's faster if you have to make minor changes and are sure of the results
18:16 &lt;mikola> I have tried the link you provided.
18:17 &lt;mikola> I can see some script like this http://awesomescreenshot.com/0ef2iw5kf7
18:17 &lt;mikola> But after clicking "Save and view summary" button I can't find appropriate option in export list.
18:18 &lt;mikola> I can see only pdf, rtf, html options. Maybe I have clicked the wrong button?
18:20 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: I'm I being totally unreasonable here? https://gist.github.com/soLEED/9675194
18:20 &lt;sdumitriu> Are you logged in as the Admin account?
18:20 &lt;sdumitriu> Only admins can access that
18:21 &lt;sdumitriu> mikola: By default you can log in with user: Admin pass: admin (case sensitive)
18:21 &lt;mikola> I guess no. I just registered simple user.
18:21 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: Hm, let me check
18:21 &lt;mikola> sdmitriu: Thanks. I think that I missed that in user guide.
18:22 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: Weird...
18:24 &lt;mikola> sdumitriu: It works with admin rights.
18:28 &lt;mikola> sdumitriu: I am quite impressed with project. The project size at my home directory is 1.2 GB and it starts with maven command and script execution. Also I am impressed because in pom.xml you have defined &lt;coverage.instructionRatio>1.00&lt;/coverage.instructionRatio>. Does it really mean 100% test coverage?
18:33 &lt;mikola> Thanks for the help. I think now I should learn some XWiki basics and setup preferred IDE to start work.
18:34 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
18:34 &lt;sdumitriu> I mean yes, 100% test coverage
18:34 &lt;sdumitriu> Although not in all modules
18:34 &lt;sdumitriu> Some are lacking tests
18:35 &lt;mikola> But this is still impressive.
18:35 &lt;sdumitriu> Thank you
18:35 &lt;sdumitriu> We're trying to keep the quality high
18:36 &lt;sdumitriu> Although when deadlines approach, we add some technical debt which should get fixed later
18:37 &lt;mikola> In projects where I participated such debt are not fixed for years :)
18:38 &lt;mikola> And I have some organizational questions.
18:39 &lt;mikola> I am planning to contribute to phenotips project as a GSOC 2014 student.
18:39 &lt;sdumitriu> We do take care of the debt from time to time
18:40 &lt;sdumitriu> When we need to revisit a module
18:40 &lt;sdumitriu> We're still cleaning up the codebase
18:40 &lt;sdumitriu> There are a few things left from the early prototyping days, but not many
18:40 &lt;sdumitriu> What projects got your attention?
18:40 &lt;mikola> I have created proposal and I want someone from organization to review it. I was communicating with Shankar Vembu and Quaid Morris.
18:41 &lt;mikola> The GSOC deadline is coming but there is still no response for my mails. I have also posted to ccm-mentors@cs.toronto.edu
18:42 &lt;mikola> I am interested in this project https://gsoc.ccm.sickkids.ca/GoogleSummerOfCode/WebHome#HDevelopmentofmachinelearningmethodsformodelingtheevolutionoftumors
18:43 &lt;akats> has quit
18:43 &lt;mikola> And the proposal can be found here: http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/proposal/public/google/gsoc2014/mikalaj/5724160613416960
18:43 &lt;sdumitriu> Well, the issue with a scientific organization is that most mentors are busy with other things; Quaid is a researcher and professor, so he's quite busy
18:44 &lt;sdumitriu> He usually answers with some delay
18:44 &lt;sdumitriu> Now, you should know that the CCM organization is an umbrella for different projects
18:44 &lt;mikola> Oh, I understand.
18:44 &lt;sdumitriu> So PhenoTips has nothing to do with that project
18:50 &lt;sdumitriu> Also, Quaid wants C code, PhenoTips is in Java
18:50 &lt;sdumitriu> You should remove the PhenoTips mentions from the proposal
18:53 &lt;mikola> Thats a fail. I thought that phylosub is some kind of backend, and phenotips is frontend.
18:54 &lt;sdumitriu> OK, the application looks good in general, but you should put more effort in the project plan / architecture part
18:54 &lt;sdumitriu> Right now it seems pretty generic and doesn't show an understanding of the project
18:55 &lt;mikola> And some clarification about organization structure. As I understand CCM has two main projects for GSOC - phenotips, and medsavand and some researcher tasks?
18:55 &lt;sdumitriu> Look at the existing Python implementation, evaluate its main components and algorithms, and come up with a more detailed architecture of your planned codebase and tools you want to use
18:56 &lt;mikola> Thanks for review.
18:56 &lt;sdumitriu> There are multiple projects developed at the CCM, check out http://ccm.sickkids.ca/?q=node/32
18:56 &lt;sdumitriu> But MedSavant and PhenoTips are the most advanced and maintained ones at the moment
18:57 &lt;sdumitriu> Some of the other projects are on life support (or just history)
18:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Other projects are more in the "researching" stage, with mainly scientific investigations going on, with a basic implementation
18:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Other projects aren't suited for GSoC since they're not open source, or they can't easily be modularized
18:59 &lt;sdumitriu> (or they're too small to be further divided)
18:59 &lt;sdumitriu> Also, GeneMania participates with another organization, NRNB
19:00 &lt;mikola> Maybe you can suggest some tools, to which I should pay attention? I thought that the main task of suggested project to research impact of parallel computation techniques and porting codebase to C++.
19:00 &lt;sdumitriu> MedSavant and PhenoTips are actively maintained, engineering-rich, big enough projects
19:02 &lt;sdumitriu> Besides that, there are also a few more research oriented ideas, like Quaid's two tumor projects, and Asha's extension for MedSavant
19:04 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, I'm not familiar with the PhyloSub code, so I can't accurately answer that
19:05 &lt;mikola> Thanks for reply and review one more time!
19:06 &lt;sdumitriu> But look at the data structures they use, would you use some standard C++ libraries instead, like STL? Or your own implementation? Or for better performance use raw structs with your own code on top?
19:07 &lt;sdumitriu> Basically, provide a more detailed plan instead of the generic "port it and improve it until it's good"
19:08 &lt;sdumitriu> Week one: convert the data structures into C++ code using the &lt;X> library
19:08 &lt;sdumitriu> Week two: start porting the Y algorithms
19:08 &lt;sdumitriu> Week three: Port the other algorithms
19:09 &lt;sdumitriu> Week four: improve these two algorithms by switching to SIMD ASM code
19:10 &lt;sdumitriu> Week five: investigate the option of running the code on FPGAs or GPUs or whatever you find better
19:11 &lt;sdumitriu> The competition is high, you don't have to just be the best coder, you have to convince us that you understood the task and paid enough attention to it to understand what needs to be done
19:19 &lt;qwebirc25631> has quit
19:24 &lt;mikola> I will definitely pay attention to existing codebase and provide more detailed plan.
19:25 &lt;bvancea> has quit
19:46 &lt;sdumitriu> tian2992: I'm looking at the code now
19:46 &lt;sdumitriu> It seems that it's not the ICPredictor that does that
19:46 &lt;sdumitriu> The document involved is PhenoTips/DiffDiagnosisService
19:47 &lt;sdumitriu> Which calls org.phenotips.solr.OmimScriptService.getDifferentialPhenotypes
19:48 &lt;mikola> has left #phenotips
20:20 &lt;Shubham> has quit
20:27 &lt;Shubham1> has quit
20:28 &lt;dev__> has quit
20:42 &lt;Shubham> has quit
21:00 &lt;Shubham> has quit
21:08 &lt;Shubham> has quit
21:14 &lt;Shubham> has quit
21:15 &lt;Guest83137> is now known as &lt;sanjhee>
22:11 &lt;sanjhee_> has quit
22:12 &lt;sanjhee> has quit
22:31 &lt;sdumitriu> is now known as &lt;sdumitriu_[Away]&gt;
23:53 &lt;ruthgrace> has quit</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.phenotipsArchive20140320</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>05bf268a-ebe7-4371-8b72-1510d27fe841</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>phenotips</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>