<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>phenotipsArchive20140227</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.sdumitriu</creator>
  <creationDate>1393485913000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.sdumitriu</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.sdumitriu</contentAuthor>
  <date>1393562181000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1393562181000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.183</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #phenotips on 27 February 2014</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
03:16 &lt;anishshah101__> has joined #phenotips
03:59 &lt;IonelPopescu> has joined #phenotips
04:17 &lt;gauravsaini03> has quit
04:21 &lt;IonelPopescu> has quit
04:33 &lt;anishshah101__> has quit
06:51 &lt;prasht63> has joined #phenotips
07:07 &lt;prasht63> has quit
07:22 &lt;IonelPopescu> has joined #phenotips
07:42 &lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
08:53 &lt;IonelPopescu> has quit
10:06 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
10:31 &lt;akats> How would I make sure that everything is installed correctly
10:58 &lt;akats> velocity can check for null correct?
10:58 &lt;vishnu93> has quit
10:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
11:17 &lt;prasht63> has quit
11:24 &lt;akats> Even if they are anonymous they can see each others' user ids or no?
11:29 &lt;ati94> has quit
11:43 &lt;mcupak> has quit
11:45 &lt;vishnu93> has joined #phenotips
11:46 &lt;akats> Do you want me to send the second email from java or from velocity?
12:30 &lt;IonelPopescu> has joined #phenotips
12:39 &lt;akats> it seems to me that the text version of the email is never used. Am I wrong?
12:41 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes you are
12:41 &lt;sdumitriu> Both parts are sent, and the mail client can decide which one to display
12:41 &lt;sdumitriu> Some mail clients don't support HTML
12:42 &lt;akats> Gotcha
12:43 &lt;gauravsaini03> hello
12:44 &lt;gauravsaini03> I am unable to find how can I edit the template, themes and pages design in pheotips ?
12:44 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: In GMail you can see it if you "Show original"
12:48 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: These are in several places, the general UI is generated by files in /templates/ on the disk, the base CSS is in /skins/colibri/colibri.css on disk, color themes can be edited in the browser (if you go to the administration -> L&amp;F -> Presentation, there's a Customize button)
12:49 &lt;gauravsaini03> thanks sdumitriu. I will look into it and do some edits
12:49 &lt;sdumitriu> Various widgets have their own styles, you should use Firebug or other developer tools to see which resources contribute to an element's style
12:55 &lt;IonelPopescu> has quit
13:30 &lt;vishnu93> hi , i'm unable to build phenotips, i keep getting this error:
13:30 &lt;vishnu93> [ERROR] [Help 1] http://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/MAVEN/AetherClassNotFound
13:30 &lt;vishnu93> a link has been provided, where there are different patches , but i still cannot go ahead
13:31 &lt;gauravsaini03> what maven version you are using ?
13:31 &lt;vishnu93> 3.2.1
13:32 &lt;gauravsaini03> I saw it mentioned in docs that maven version 3.0.4 is recommended
13:32 &lt;gauravsaini03> Can you please try building it with 3.0.4
13:32 &lt;vishnu93> ok i will
13:52 &lt;IonelPopescu> has joined #phenotips
14:00 &lt;gauravsaini03> sdumitriu: Will directly changing to templates velocity files will saw the changes ?
14:01 &lt;gauravsaini03> I tried changing the vm files but changes are not shown !
14:08 &lt;akats> Hi
14:09 &lt;akats> Maven 3.0.5 Works, 3.1.x does not
14:10 &lt;akats> gauravsaini03: You tried changing the vm files where?
14:11 &lt;gauravsaini03> I tried changing in the folder which I extracted after build.
14:11 &lt;gauravsaini03> phenotips-standalone-1.0-SNAPSHOT-2014-02-25/webapps/phenotips/templates
14:14 &lt;akats> And you've restarted the server I'm assuming
14:17 &lt;gauravsaini03> yes
14:17 &lt;gauravsaini03> I have restarted it
14:17 &lt;akats> In any case, those files are not the files you want to practice on
14:18 &lt;akats> What you want to learn to do is working with velocity in the browser
14:18 &lt;akats> For example, open the home page and press ctrl+g
14:19 &lt;akats> Type patientsheet
14:19 &lt;akats> Select any of the files and press edit
14:19 &lt;akats> click*
14:20 &lt;akats> And don't forget to be logged in as admin
14:20 &lt;gauravsaini03> ok.
14:23 &lt;gauravsaini03> Actually I have to work on the overall theme of the phenotips
14:23 &lt;gauravsaini03> That is why looking for its templating system and how its working.
14:23 &lt;nclandrei> has joined #phenotips
14:23 &lt;gauravsaini03> where is the html div and classes and structure are defined for various page
14:23 &lt;nclandrei> hi guys :-)
14:24 &lt;akats> Hello nclandrei
14:25 &lt;akats> gauravsaini03: the files in the template folder are mainly (probably all of them actually) xwiki files
14:25 &lt;nclandrei> how is it going? ( am I allowed to be more informal)
14:27 &lt;akats> I personally don't see a problem. We're doing good on this end.
14:27 &lt;akats> Hope you're well too
14:28 &lt;akats> so gauravsaini if you're looking ti change anything from the phenotips project then you'd look in a different place
14:28 &lt;akats> we have a lot of css defined in objects which are attached to documents
14:28 &lt;akats> it's a little hard to grasp at first
14:29 &lt;akats> so what you need to have is a thorough understanding of the xwiki object model
14:30 &lt;gauravsaini03> yes, that is what I am thinking to do. I have to look into the xwiki structure and see how themming works
14:30 &lt;nclandrei> perfect.. whenever someone is willing to talk to me about the Support Multiple Visits for Phenotips, I would be glad to share my new idea :-D I had one one before, but this one I think is somehow better
14:34 &lt;akats> nclandrei I would not be the person to talk to, so you all have to wait.
14:35 &lt;nclandrei> sure then :D
14:35 &lt;nclandrei> akats: are you one of the mentors as well?
14:38 &lt;akats> Yes I am
14:38 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: Some templates are being overwritten in the PhenoTips.Skin document
14:38 &lt;sdumitriu> http://localhost:8080/bin/view/PhenoTips/Skin?viewer=attachments
14:39 &lt;sdumitriu> And http://localhost:8080/bin/edit/PhenoTips/Skin?editor=object&amp;classname=XWiki.XWikiSkins&amp;object=0
14:39 &lt;gauravsaini03> ok.
14:40 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: http://platform.xwiki.org/xwiki/bin/view/DevGuide/Skins might be of help
14:40 &lt;sdumitriu> nclandrei: Hi
14:40 &lt;gauravsaini03> But If I have to commit that back to phenotips, as I am working on developing a template that support mobile and responsive in a way
14:43 &lt;akats> gauravsaini03: You have several options
14:44 &lt;akats> The easiest is to edit the file in the browser. Test that everything works. Then choose to export as xar
14:44 &lt;akats> Then overwrite the file on disk
14:45 &lt;nclandrei> sdumitriu: Hello how are you?
14:47 &lt;sdumitriu> nclandrei: Busy busy
14:48 &lt;gauravsaini03> So, akats so Can I change the header of the phenotips UI in the browser itself ?
14:49 &lt;sdumitriu> gauravsaini03: Yes
14:50 &lt;sdumitriu> But which parts of the header? Most of the HTML is generated in the skin object, http://localhost:8080/bin/edit/PhenoTips/Skin?editor=object&amp;classname=XWiki.XWikiSkins&amp;object=0&amp;property=header.vm
14:53 &lt;nclandrei> @sdumitriu: when you have some spare time I might share another idea with you if possible :D
14:53 &lt;gauravsaini03> oh Thanks alot sdumitriu :)
14:53 &lt;gauravsaini03> I figured out now :)
14:53 &lt;sdumitriu> nclandrei: Shoot, I'll read when I have some spare seconds
15:05 &lt;nclandrei> so I had an idea today, which might mean to somehow incorporate some code of MySQL and PHP on the front end.. what it is actually
15:06 &lt;nclandrei> we shall give each user who wants to collaborate on a project with other users
15:06 &lt;nclandrei> an unique id
15:07 &lt;nclandrei> and whenever we want to modify something
15:09 &lt;nclandrei> there will be an adress on let's say the server behind phenom central specific for that unique id
15:09 &lt;nclandrei> and using mysql we can interconnect them and make an interface which would incorporate all the changes made by multiple ids
15:09 &lt;nclandrei> on a patient
15:14 &lt;akats> nclandrei: Do you think you can implement your idea wholly through xwiki?
15:14 &lt;nclandrei> I think it's not impossible, I know I will encounter challenges on my way
15:14 &lt;nclandrei> some of them quite big, but I am sure that eventually it can be acomplished
15:15 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: Can you take a look at the UI when you have a minute
15:15 &lt;akats> nclandrei: adding PHP and MySQL into the mix would create even bigger problems
15:16 &lt;nclandrei> well my big question remains the same.. how can we then store all the necessary info regarding multiple visits
15:16 &lt;nclandrei> if we don't have a place to do that?
15:17 &lt;nclandrei> that would be cool if we could add an additional interface, let's call it that way, on phenom central's one and just use some mysql and php
15:24 &lt;akats> I've got a possible solution for you
15:25 &lt;akats> It will not make sense however if you have not become familiar with the xwiki object model
15:25 &lt;akats> One sec actually
15:25 &lt;nclandrei> sure
15:29 &lt;akats> I'm going to leave your questions for sdumitriu to answer. The only thing I can say is that PHP would not be a good road to go down.
15:30 &lt;sdumitriu> Indeed, no PHP or MySQL
15:30 &lt;sdumitriu> XWiki is a web application development platform
15:30 &lt;vishnu93> has quit
15:30 &lt;sdumitriu&gt; It has its own storage and coding paradigms
15:31 &lt;nclandrei> okay then, this idea is being dropped
15:31 &lt;sdumitriu> You can store any (simple) type of data using its data model: http://platform.xwiki.org/xwiki/bin/view/DevGuide/DataModel
15:32 &lt;sdumitriu> And you can write a lot of code in Velocity, using either the core APIs or custom services writen in Java
15:32 &lt;nclandrei> hmm
15:32 &lt;sdumitriu> But the project description already gives hints about what's expected
15:32 &lt;nclandrei> could we make a database tree list?
15:33 &lt;nclandrei> yes true, but I was wondering if we could implement other technologies as well
15:33 &lt;nclandrei> I am sorry
15:33 &lt;sdumitriu> The idea is to change the linear history with a branched one
15:34 &lt;sdumitriu> (you can actually write PHP code in XWiki if you really want: http://extensions.xwiki.org/xwiki/bin/view/Extension/PHP+Macro )
15:34 &lt;nclandrei> yes but if you really say so it wouldn't be such a good idea
15:34 &lt;sdumitriu> (but as you'll grow older you'll realize that PHP is actually one of the worst programming languages ever)
15:34 &lt;nclandrei> haha
15:34 &lt;nclandrei> my uncle says that too
15:35 &lt;nclandrei> then yes.. I mean I've researched quite some time upon a multitude of variants
15:35 &lt;nclandrei> it seems that either this one which I've presented could be a possiblity
15:35 &lt;nclandrei> but I'll drop it
15:35 &lt;nclandrei> thanks for the advice
15:35 &lt;nclandrei> and the other one is using jGit
15:36 &lt;nclandrei> that would be manageable to transform the linear history to branched..
15:37 &lt;sdumitriu> The goal is to provide a different implementation for https://github.com/xwiki/xwiki-platform/blob/master/xwiki-platform-core/xwiki-platform-oldcore/src/main/java/com/xpn/xwiki/store/XWikiVersioningStoreInterface.java than https://github.com/xwiki/xwiki-platform/blob/master/xwiki-platform-core/xwiki-platform-oldcore/src/main/java/com/xpn/xwiki/store/XWikiHibernateVersioningStore.java
15:38 &lt;sdumitriu> (and at the same time change that interface to be more powerful, since it's a 9 years old interface that needs a refresh)
15:40 &lt;nclandrei> yes I've understood.. so in my application I should state how would I tackle this issue
15:40 &lt;nclandrei> right?
15:40 &lt;nclandrei> like a plan with what challenges I might encounter
15:43 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
15:49 &lt;nclandrei> good
15:49 &lt;nclandrei> thanks
15:52 &lt;nclandrei> how is work going? :D
16:11 &lt;nclandrei> well I am going to bed (-: have a nice evening
16:11 &lt;nclandrei> and talk to you tomorrow
16:11 &lt;nclandrei> has quit
16:25 &lt;akats> how do I lock edit access to admin?
16:26 &lt;sdumitriu> So that only Admin can edit the document?
16:52 &lt;akats> sent the request. I'll check it over now
17:05 &lt;gauravsaini03> has quit
17:09 &lt;akats> made the fixes
17:10 &lt;akats> I have to go in half an hour, so I want to make sure that everything is perfect before I go.
17:18 &lt;akats> Fixed the last one too
17:20 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: Merged
17:20 &lt;sdumitriu> You can do one more quick thing: add access rights to the other documents in the data space
17:21 &lt;akats> kk
17:21 &lt;akats> and tomorrow if you're not here early again I'll just start on the other issue
17:21 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
17:22 &lt;akats> which was related to adding users
17:22 &lt;akats> that took me long enough to remember
17:25 &lt;akats> XWikiRights correct?
17:25 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
17:25 &lt;sdumitriu> XWikiAdminGroup
17:26 &lt;sdumitriu> edit
17:26 &lt;sdumitriu> allow
17:35 &lt;akats> done. though most likely missed something
17:39 &lt;akats> has quit
18:02 &lt;IonelPopescu> has quit
18:18 &lt;nairboon> has quit
23:13 &lt;gauravsaini03> has joined #phenotips
23:36 &lt;gaurav_> has joined #phenotips
23:36 &lt;gauravsaini03> has quit</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.phenotipsArchive20140227</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>13b1f107-89f5-4af6-a3c3-8372501ada5d</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>phenotips</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>