<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.1">
  <web>IRC</web>
  <name>phenotipsArchive20140331</name>
  <language />
  <defaultLanguage />
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.sdumitriu</creator>
  <creationDate>1396276277000</creationDate>
  <parent>IRC.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.sdumitriu</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.sdumitriu</contentAuthor>
  <date>1396314246000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1396314246000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.58</version>
  <title>IRC Archive for channel #phenotips on 31 March 2014</title>
  <comment>Logging from IRC</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>plain/1.0</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>&lt;allasm> has quit
10:31 &lt;allasm> has joined #phenotips
12:06 &lt;bvancea> has joined #phenotips
12:24 &lt;akats> has joined #phenotips
12:58 &lt;akats> Michael is probably right. The approach of taking the category doesn't seem to be working too well. Going one step up the tree is probably best.
12:59 &lt;sdumitriu> Why?
13:02 &lt;akats> Well if the two patients are matched on the same phenotype, then it gives the category which is that phenotype. Actually now that I think about it, this is the only case for which it makes sense to go up the tree. So that's something I should do, rather than always going up the tree.
13:04 &lt;sdumitriu> OK, sounds good
13:54 &lt;akats> We have a slight problem. Due to recent changes in PhenoTips repo, particularly in Feature and Patient interfaces, the Patient-Network repo does not build.
13:54 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, working on that repo later today
13:54 &lt;sdumitriu> The build has been failing for a week
13:54 &lt;sdumitriu> Are you sure you have the latest version?
13:55 &lt;akats> I just pulled it. But I'll double check.
13:55 &lt;akats> Up to date
13:56 &lt;sdumitriu> OK, will check really soon
13:57 &lt;akats> I'm building the remote project for a fresh install test, should I just roll back my
13:57 &lt;akats> PhenoTips?
13:58 &lt;sdumitriu> What remote project?
13:58 &lt;akats> Gene matcher
13:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Right
13:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm, no
13:58 &lt;sdumitriu> Can it wait an hour?
13:58 &lt;akats> Sure. I'll go for lunch then.
13:58 &lt;akats> Perfect actually
15:41 &lt;sdumitriu> akats: The build should be working now
15:43 &lt;akats> Thank you!
16:03 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: I have a few components that are trying to overwrite each other. I've deleted the duplicates (the ones that have a date attached to them), but there are still a few overwrite warnings left. Off the top of your head, any ideas?
16:16 &lt;bvancea> has quit
16:26 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: Has anyone built phenomecentral after all the pushes?
16:26 &lt;sdumitriu> Only Jenkins
16:28 &lt;akats> Well, I built it once. Added patient-network, and my stuff. Ended up with "double" header on the front page. Thinking that maybe it's something I did, I rebuilt phenomecentral and ran it by itself. Still have a double header, and got errors
16:28 &lt;akats> com.xpn.xwiki.XWikiException: Error number 3002 in 3: The attachment could not be found in the filesystem attachment store.
16:29 &lt;akats> All of them like this one, it seems
16:29 &lt;sdumitriu> Right, that's a known issue
16:29 &lt;sdumitriu> There's a bug in one of the XWiki Maven plugins
16:29 &lt;sdumitriu> You can fix it by going to the administration, and import the full pc xar
16:30 &lt;akats> "full pc"? As in PhenoTips?
16:31 &lt;akats> oh phenomecentral
16:31 &lt;sdumitriu> PhenomeCentral
16:51 &lt;akats> Hmm... didn't fix the problem on either instances. Just to clarify, you mean to go to import and select phenomecentral.org/ui/target/*.xar and import all, correct?
16:51 &lt;sdumitriu> Yes
17:13 &lt;akats> This is one of these days. I tried replacing PatientSheet, all UIX files, and some others from the PhenoTips target xar, but it didn't help. I still get this error when opening the "Clinical symptoms" tab. I don't want to distract you from work, so if you'd don't have off the top of the head solution, I'll give it a go. https://gist.github.com/soLEED/44d06261aebd1c98f802
17:14 &lt;sdumitriu> You need to update the version of commons-lang3 that's in libs
17:14 &lt;sdumitriu> We've updated to 3.3.1 last week
17:15 &lt;akats> Gotcha
17:24 &lt;akats> sdumitriu: Just a heads up, the problem wasn't the new version missing, it was the old version still being there.
17:24 &lt;sdumitriu> OK
17:24 &lt;sdumitriu> It shouldn't be in a clean install
17:30 &lt;sdumitriu> allasm: When disabling "Allow user tokens", pushing always fails
17:31 &lt;sdumitriu> allasm: What's the intended behavior for that?
17:39 &lt;sdumitriu> allasm: When updates are disabled, the Push UI should not allow that option to be selected
17:57 &lt;mcupak> has quit
18:10 &lt;akats> There's a bug in the "Phenotypic features breakdown", but I think it's not in my code. When looking at the breakdown, for the info for the current patient (not the remote) is "The current patient (P0000004) presented with: Undisclosed information"
18:11 &lt;sdumitriu> Hm...
18:36 &lt;akats> has quit
21:03 &lt;sdumitriu> has quit
21:04 &lt;sdumitriu> has joined #phenotips</content>
  <object>
    <name>IRC.phenotipsArchive20140331</name>
    <number>0</number>
    <className>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</className>
    <guid>f0635313-1659-42dd-9727-30a3bcecb47d</guid>
    <class>
      <name>IRC.IRCBotArchiveClass</name>
      <customClass />
      <customMapping />
      <defaultViewSheet />
      <defaultEditSheet />
      <defaultWeb />
      <nameField />
      <validationScript />
      <channel>
        <customDisplay />
        <disabled>0</disabled>
        <name>channel</name>
        <number>1</number>
        <picker>0</picker>
        <prettyName>Channel</prettyName>
        <size>30</size>
        <unmodifiable>0</unmodifiable>
        <validationMessage />
        <validationRegExp />
        <classType>com.xpn.xwiki.objects.classes.StringClass</classType>
      </channel>
    </class>
    <property>
      <channel>phenotips</channel>
    </property>
  </object>
</xwikidoc>